Thank you.
You don't like flying, do you?
Who gives you that idea?
You want to know the secret to surviving air travel?
After you get where you're going, take off your shoes and your socks, then you walk around on the rug barefoot and make fists with your toes.
Fists with your toes?
I know.
It sounds crazy.
Trust me.
I've been doing it for nine years.
Yes, sir.
Better than a shower and a hot cup of coffee.
OK.
It's OK.
I'm a cop.
Trust me.
I've been doing this for 11 years.
The captain and crew would like to welcome you to Los Angeles.
Have a very merry Christmas.
Put my bag here, you.
Flight 247 to Tucson at 8.42.
Ladies and gentlemen!
I want to congratulate each and every one of you for making this one of the greatest years in the history of the Nakatomi Corporation.
On behalf of the Chief Executive Officer, Mr. Ozu, and the Board of Directors, we thank you one and all and wish you a Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year.
Merry Christmas!
Hey, Holly.
What about dinner tonight, huh?
Harry, it's Christmas Eve.
Families, stockings.
Chestnuts.
Rudolph and Frosty.
Any of these things ring a bell?
Actually, I was thinking more of mulled wine, a nice aged brie, and a roaring fireplace.
You know what I'm saying?
Ginny, it's 5.40.
Go join the party.
Have some champagne.
You're making me feel like Ebenezer Scrooge.
Thanks a lot, Miss DeNiro.
Do you think the baby can handle a little sip?
That baby's ready to tend bar.
Last chance.
Bye.
McLean, ladies.
Lucy McLean speaking.
Hello, Lucy McLean.
This is your mother speaking.
Pretty soon.
You'll be in bed when I get there, though.
Let me talk to Paulina, OK, hon?
And no snooping around the house looking for presents.
Is Daddy coming home with you?
Well, we'll see what Santa and Mommy can do, OK?
Put Paulina on.
Bye, honey.
Hola, Mrs. Holly.
Um, did Mr. McClain call?
No, Mrs. Holly.
No telefono.
Well, he probably just didn't have time before his flight.
Um, it might be a good idea to make up the spare bedroom just in case.
Si, Mrs. Holly.
I do that already.
What would I do without you, Paulina?
California.
Hey, I'm John McClain.
Argonne.
I'm your limo driver.
Nice bear.
OK.
Argyle, what do we do now?
I was hoping you could tell me.
It's my first time driving a limo.
It's OK.
It's my first time riding in one.
Relax.
We got everything in this mug, man.
Look at this.
CD, CB, TV, telephone, full bar, VHS.
If your friends have to trot, you know, a few mama bears we can hook up with.
Or is he married?
He's married.
OK.
Oh, sorry about that.
It's the girl's day off.
I didn't know you were going to sit up front.
So your lady live out here?
About the past six months.
Meaning you still live in New York?
You always ask this many questions, Argyle.
Sorry, man.
I used to drive a cab, and people would expect a little chitchat.
So you divorced?
Just drive the car, man.
Hey, come on.
You divorced?
You separated?
She beat you up?
She had a good job, turned into a great career.
Well, that meant she had to move here.
You're very fast, Argyle.
So why didn't you come?
Well, why didn't you come with her, man?
What's up?
I'm a New York cop.
I got a six-month backlog of New York scumbags I'm still trying to put behind bars.
I can't just pick up and go that easy.
In other words, you thought she wasn't going to make it out here, and she'd come crawling on back to you.
So why bother to pack, right?
Like I said, you're very fast, Argon.
Mind if we hear some tunes?
Hey, out of work.
You got any Christmas music?
This is Christmas music!
So your lady sees you, you run into each other's arms, the music comes up, and you live happily ever after, right?
I can live with that.
So if it doesn't work out, man, you got a place to stay?
I'll find a place.
I'll tell you what.
I'm going to pull in the parking garage, and I'll wait.
You score, you give me a call in the car farm.
I'll take your bags to the desk.
You strike out, I'll get you a hotel.
You're all right, Argyle.
Just remember that when you sign for the tip.
Hi.
Good evening.
I'm here to see Holly McLean.
Just type it in there.
Cute toy.
Yeah.
If you have to take a leak, it'll even help you find your zipper.
30th floor.
The party.
They're the only ones left in the building.
Take the express elevator.
Get off where you hear the noise.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
Champagne, sir?
Thank you.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Hey!
Merry Christmas!
Fucking California.
Why don't I talk to him right now?
Hi.
I'm looking for... Holly Gennaro.
Yeah.
Then you must be John McClain.
Joe Takagi.
Hi.
How was your ride in?
Nice.
May I have you to thank for that?
Seemed the least we could do.
It's quite a place you have here.
It will be if we ever get it finished.
There's still several floors under construction.
Holly went to the vault room to fax some documents.
She should be back any minute.
In the meanwhile, her office is right back here.
Alice.
I was just making a call, and this was the nurse's phone.
I want you to meet John McClain.
Holly's husband?
Holly's policeman?
Alice is in charge of international development.
Heard a heck of a lot about you.
Missed something.
Can I get you anything?
Food, cake?
Some watered-down champagne?
No, thank you.
I'm fine.
You throw quite a party.
I didn't realize they celebrated Christmas in Japan.
We're flexible.
Girl lover didn't work out, so we got you with tape decks.
Actually, it's sort of a double celebration.
We closed a pretty big deal today, and a lot of it was due to Holly.
Am I right, JoJo?
We haven't gotten the performance.
Have you met everyone?
Oh, we've been sticking him with spears.
Of course he has.
She was made for the business.
Tough as new.
I was hoping you made that polite.
Show him the watch.
Later.
Well, go on.
Show him.
What, are you embarrassed?
It's just a small token of appreciation for all our hard work.
It's a Rolex.
I'm sure I'll see you later.
Is there a place where I could wash up?
Sure.
I have to forgive Ellis.
He gets very depressed this time of year.
He thought he was God's greatest gift, you know?
Yeah, another type.
Think he's got his eye on you.
It's OK.
I have my eye on his private bathroom.
Where are you staying?
Things happen so fast, I didn't get a chance to ask you on the phone.
Cappy Roberts retired out here.
Oh, yeah?
Told me I could bunk in with him.
Cappy retired, huh?
Where does he live?
Ramona.
Pomona.
Huh?
Yeah.
Glad you'll be in the car half the time.
Why don't we make it easy?
I have a spare bedroom.
I mean, it's not huge or anything, but kids would love to have you at the house.
They would, huh?
I would, too.
Sorry.
I missed you.
I guess you didn't miss my name, though, huh?
Except maybe when you're signing checks.
Since when did you start using Ms.
Gennaro?
It's a Japanese company.
They figure a married woman's got more power.
You are a married woman, Holly.
You're married to me.
No, we're going to have this conversation again.
We did this in July.
We never finished this conversation in July.
I had an opportunity.
I had to take it.
Yeah, right.
No matter what the consequences, no matter what it did to our marriage, you had to take this opportunity.
It didn't do anything to our marriage except maybe change your idea of what our marriage should be.
I don't think you have a clue as to what my idea of our marriage should be, Holly.
I know exactly what your idea of our marriage should be.
Mr. Nero, I... Excuse me.
Um, Mr. Takagi is looking for you.
He wants you to say something to the troops.
Thank you.
Speech time.
Be back in a few minutes.
That was great, John.
Good job.
Very mature.
So Kareem rebounds, right?
Feeds Worthy on the break.
Over to AC to Magic, then back to Worthy, right?
Boom!
Two points.
We're in.
Da, da, da, da.
Hmm.
Son of a bitch.
Fists with your toes.
Yeah, our guy.
All right, where are you?
I'm kicking it down in the garage.
What's the word with your new lady, man?
The vote's not in yet.
Hey, brother.
Moment.
No, no, no!
Wait!
R-Guy?
I'm back, you there?
Hello?
Show the numbers, use it!
Ah!
Stay calm.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Due to the Nakatomi Corporation's legacy of greed around the globe, they're about to be taught a lesson in the real use of power.
You will be witnesses.
Now.
Where is Mr. Takagi?
Joseph Yoshinobu Takagi.
Born Kyoto, 1937.
Family emigrated to San Pedro, California, 1939.
Interned Manzanar, 1942 to 43.
Scholarship student, University of California.
1955.
Law degree, Stanford, 1962.
MBA, Harvard, 1970.
President, Nakatomi Trading.
Vice chairman, Nakatomi Investment Group.
Enough.
And father of five.
I am Takagi.
How do you do?
It's a pleasure to meet you.
32 construction, 33 computers.
Do-do-do-do-do-do-do.
Nice suit.
John Phillips, London.
I have two myself.
Rumour has it Arafat buys his there.
On the left, on the left.
And when Alexander saw the breadth of his domain, he wept, for there were no more worlds to conquer.
Benefits of a classical education.
Oh, that's beautiful.
I always enjoyed to make models when I was a boy.
The exactness, the attention to every conceivable detail.
It's beautiful.
Is this what this is all about?
Our project in Indonesia?
Contrary to what you people may think, you're going to develop that reason, not exploit it.
I believe you.
I read the article in Forbes.
Mr. Takagi.
I could talk about industrialization and men's fashions all day, but I'm afraid work must intrude and my associate Theo has some questions for you.
Sort of fill-in-the-blanks questions, actually.
I don't have that code.
You broke in here to access our computer?
Any information you could get when they wake up in Tokyo in the morning, they'll change it.
You won't be able to blackmail our executives, threaten our property.
Sit down.
Mr. Takagi, I'm really not interested in your computer.
But I need the code key because I am interested in the $640 million in negotiable bearer bonds that you have locked in your vault.
And the computer controls the vault.
You want money?
What kind of terrorists are you?
Who said we were terrorists?
The bonds represent, at most, ten days of operating capital for your parent organization.
No more than temporary.
The code, please.
It's useless to you.
There are seven safeguards on our vault and the code key is only one of them.
You'll never get it open.
Then there's no reason not to tell it to us.
I told you.
It's not over yet.
It's a very nice suit, Mr. Takagi.
To be ashamed to ruin it.
I'm going to count to three.
There will not be a four.
Give me the code.
One.
Two.
Three.
I don't know it, I'm telling you.
Get on the jet to Tokyo and ask the chairman.
I'm telling you, you're just gonna have to kill me.
Okay.
We do it the hard way.
Tony, see if you can dispose of that.
Carl, you better go and check on Heinrich's work up on the machine floor.
Sire Heinrich, now you can break the code.
He didn't bring me along for my charming personality.
Margo, tell me you heard the shots and you're calling the police right now.
Of course I'm still coming by late.
I'm on my way to Vegas.
Uli, get up on the pipes.
Marco, you go through here.
I'll throw you the cord.
Hans, we're on the roof.
30 minutes to break the code.
Two hours, two and a half hours for the five mechanicals, at the minimum.
The seventh lock, however, is out of my hands.
I'm sorry.
The seventh lock, the electromagnetic seal.
You do understand the circuits cannot be cut locally.
Trust me.
Why the fuck didn't you stop him, John?
Because then you'd be dead too, asshole.
Think, goddammit, think.
We've got a fire alarm.
Call 911.
Give them the guard's name, the building code number, and cancel the alarm.
Then disable the system.
Are they on what floor did the alarm go off?
Matt, shall we go?
Nein.
Come on, baby.
Come to papa.
Kiss your fucking Dalmatian.
Oh, you stupid motherfuckers!
No!
Turn the fucking truck around!
The fire has been called off, my friend.
No one is coming to help you.
You might as well come out and join the others.
I promise I won't hurt you.
Drop it, dickhead.
It's the police.
You won't hurt me.
Yeah?
Why not?
Because you're a policeman.
There are rules for policemen.
Yeah.
That's what my captain keeps telling me.
9 million terrorists in the world and I gotta kill one with feet smaller than my sister.
I wanted this to be professional, efficient, adult, cooperative, not a lot to ask.
Alas, your Mr. Takagi did not see it that way, so he won't be joining us for the rest of his life.
We can go anywhere you want us.
You can walk out of here or be carried out.
But have no illusions, we are in charge.
So, decide now, each of you.
And please remember, we have left nothing to chance.
Get them back!
Now I have a machine gun.
Ho, ho, ho.
A security guard we missed?
Usually tired old policemen growing fat on a pension.
No, no, no.
This is something else.
We have to do something, Hans.
Yes, we do.
Tell Carl his brother is dead.
Tell him to come down.
Franco, you and Fritz take the body upstairs and out of sight.
I don't want the hostages to think too much.
I want blood!
You'll have it.
But let Heinrich plant the detonators and Theo prepare the vault.
After we call the police, they'll waste hours trying to negotiate, and then you can tear the building apart looking for this man.
But until then, we do not alter the plan.
And if he alters it... What do you think?
Something's wrong.
Cops?
John.
Oh, Christ, he can fuck this whole thing up.
What does he think he's doing?
His job.
Bullshit.
His job's 3,000 miles away.
Without him, we still have a chance we might be able to get out of here.
Tell that to Dekagi.
Mayday, mayday, anyone copying Channel 9?
Terrorists have seized the Nakatomi building and are holding at least 30 people hostage.
I repeat, unknown number of terrorists, six or more armed with automatic weapons at Nakatomi Plaza, Century City.
Where's the best place to transmit?
Somebody answer me, goddammit!
The roof.
Go, go!
It's the same address as that fire signal.
I'll handle it.
Attention, whoever you are.
This channel is reserved for emergency calls only.
No fucking shit, lady!
Do I sound like I'm ordering a pizza?
No one kills him but me.
They have already killed one hostage.
They are fortifying their positions while you're jerking me off on the radio.
Now send the police back up ASAP.
Sir, I've already told you.
This is a reserve channel.
If this is an emergency call, dial 911 on your telephone.
Otherwise, I'll have to report this as an FCC violation.
Fine.
Report me.
Come the fuck down here and arrest
See if there's a black and white that can do a drive-by.
I thought you guys just ate donuts.
They're for my wife.
Yeah.
She's pregnant.
Bag it.
Big time.
Thanks.
Dispatch to 8 Lincoln 30, over.
This is 8 Lincoln 30.
Come on in, over.
Investigate a Code 2 at Nakatomi Plaza, Century City.
8 Lincoln 30 to dispatch.
I'm on my way.
Shit, where the fuck...
Perfect.
The elevators are locked off.
You can't escape.
Just shut it in and come back down.
Carl, the police are probably on their way already.
I can stall them, but not if they hear gunshots.
If you lock him in, he'll be neutralized.
Come out to the coast, we'll get together, have a few laughs.
I don't know what a TV dinner feels like.
Call the police!
It's about time.
No signs of disturbance, dispatch.
8030, roger.
Possible crank call.
Check the area again and confirm.
He's driving his car.
Stevie Wonder?
I do see a guard inside.
I'm going to go in for a closer look.
803D, roger.
Use caution.
Eddie?
I had a feeling you'd be calling.
Evening, officer.
What can I do for you?
We had that false alarm, you know.
They asked me, that goddamn computer sent you out on another wild goose chase.
They've been chasing bugs in this system ever since they installed it.
Oh, shit.
Come on, I got 50 bucks bet on them assholes.
Come on, come on, where's the fucking cavalry?
Where is he?
Marco, he's at 34.
Go, quick, 34.
Do it.
It was good for 52 yards.
You don't mind if I take a look around, do you?
No, help yourself.
We have seven seconds left in this first period.
Seven to nothing, Notre Dame.
The Irish driving 74 yards and eight plays with... Put this fucker down.
Tree, motherfucker, drop it!
Put that fucking gun down!
Put the gun down!
Okay, wait now!
Don't shoot!
Oh, the hell with this.
You are done.
No more table.
Where are you going, pal?
Next time you have a chance to kill someone, don't hesitate.
Thanks for the advice.
Sorry to waste your time.
No problem at all.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas to you.
Outside is frightful.
Dum-da-dum, delightful.
For the love.
8 Lincoln 30 to dispatch.
8-0-30, go ahead.
Yeah, that's a wild goose chase over here at Nakatomi Plaza.
Everything here is OK.
Over.
But nobody has no place to go.
Let it snow, let it snow, let it snow.
Welcome to the party, pal!
Goddamn it!
I need backup assistance now!
Now, goddamn it, now!
Monica, I can get us a table.
Wolfgang and I are very close friends.
I interviewed him, for God's sake.
I'm in Nakatomi Plus.
They're turning my car into Swiss cheese.
I need backup assistance now!
Now, goddammit, now!
I just thought I'd love to hear that sound.
All of you, relax.
This is a matter of inconvenient timing.
That's all.
Police action was inevitable.
And as it happens, necessary.
So let them fumble about outside and stay calm.
This is simply the beginning.
I thought I told all of you I want radio silence until further... I'm sorry, Hans.
I didn't get that message.
Wax Tony and Marco and his friend here, I figured you and Carl and Franco might be a little lonely, so I wanted to give you a call.
How does he know so much about this?
This is very kind of you.
I assume you are our mysterious party crush.
You are most troublesome for a security guard.
Sorry, Hans, wrong guess.
Would you like to go for double jeopardy where the scores can really change?
Oh, these are very bad for you.
Who are you, then?
Just a fly in the ointment, Hearns.
The monkey in the wrench.
The pain in the ass.
Whoa.
Check on all the others.
Don't use the radio.
See if he's lying about Marco and find out if anyone else is missing.
Mr. Mystery Guest.
Yeah, I'm still here.
Unless you want to open the front door for me.
No, I'm afraid not.
But you have me at a loss.
You know my name, but who are you?
Just another American who saw too many movies as a child.
Another orphan of a bankrupt culture who thinks he's John Wayne, Rambo, Marshall Dillon.
I was always kind of partial to Roy Rogers, actually.
I really like those sequined shirts.
Do you really think you have a chance against us, Mr. Cowboy?
Yippee-ki-yay, motherfucker.
I can get the jump on everybody if I get a remote.
Sam, I don't have the new pages.
Where's the... Harvey, keep your pants on, will ya?
Sam, look, I'm begging you.
Simon's already had a remote thing with that Santa sing-along.
I'll tell him to swing by or something.
I'm not sitting on this.
I don't want to hear it.
This is my story.
I am going out there.
I can't hear you.
Sam, all right, look.
Sam, I'll tell you what.
You don't want to give me a truck, I'll go and I'll steal a truck.
Hey, give us a break, Thornburg.
Eat it, Harvey.
4, 3, 2, 1.
Harvey, we're on the air.
Good evening.
This is Harvey Johnson.
And I'm Gail Wallens, and this is Nightline News at 10.
Our top stories on this Christmas Eve, the high tides... Take truck number five and get out of here.
...for a minicam report to Malibu.
He wasn't lying about Marco.
He's down on the street.
And the other man was Heinrich.
And his bag is missing.
He had the detonator.
Here.
Yo!
We may have some problems.
How's our schedule?
Three down, four to go.
Then don't waste time talking to me.
This is Sergeant Al Powell of the Los Angeles Police Department.
If the person who radioed for help can hear me on this channel, acknowledge this transmission.
I say again, if the person who radioed for help on this channel can hear me, acknowledge this transmission.
I read you, pal.
You the guy in the car?
What's left of him.
Can you identify yourself?
Not now.
Maybe later.
Listen fast.
This is a party line.
The neighbors got itchy trigger fingers.
All right, here's the deal.
You got 30 or so hostages on the 30th floor.
The leader's here.
His name's Hans.
We have to find him and shut him up.
He's telling them everything.
Let him.
I'm waiting for the FBI to arrive.
Until then, he can waste as much time as he likes.
But we must find the bag.
Fritz, go help Uli.
We must have the detonators.
They got missiles, automatic weapons, and enough plastic explosives to orbit Arnold Schwarzenegger.
They're down to nine now, counting the skydiver you met.
These guys are mostly European, judging by their clothing labels.
Cigarettes.
They're well financed and very slick.
Well, now how do you know that?
I seen enough phony IDs in my time to recognize that the ones they got must have cost a fortune.
Add all that up, I don't know what the fuck it means, but you got some badass perpetrators and they're here to stay.
I hear you, partner.
L.A.'
's finest aronid.
So light him if you got him.
Way ahead of you, partner.
Call me Roy.
Well, listen up, Roy.
If you think of anything else you think we need to know, don't be shy, OK?
In the meantime, I want you to find a safe place to hole up and let us do our job, understand?
All right, who's talking, Kong?
I am, sir.
Sergeant Powell, Al Powell.
Dwayne Robinson.
Powell, what's the deal here?
What do these pricks want?
Well, if you mean the terrorists, sir, we don't exactly know.
We haven't heard a peep from them.
Well, who in the hell have you been talking to?
We don't know that either, sir.
He won't give us his name.
But he appears to be the one who phoned in the report.
He's killed one terrorist for sure, and he claims he's capped off two others.
He claims?
Powell, has it occurred to you he could be one of the terrorists pulling your chain?
Or some nutcase in there?
I don't think so, sir.
In fact, I think he's a cop.
Maybe not LAPD, but he's definitely a badge.
How do you know that?
A hunch.
Things he said.
Like being able to spot a phony ID.
Jesus Christ, Powell.
Could be a fucking bartender for all we know.
TV's here.
I have a request.
What idiot put you in charge?
You did.
When you murdered my boss.
Now everybody's looking to me.
Personally, I pass on the job.
I don't enjoy being this close to you.
Go on.
We have a pregnant woman out there.
Relax, she's not due for a couple of weeks.
But sitting on that rock isn't doing her back any good.
So I would like permission to move her to one of the offices where there's a sofa.
No, but I'll have a sofa brought out to you.
Good enough?
Good enough.
And unless you like it messy, I'd start bringing us in groups to the bathroom.
Yes, you're right.
It will be done.
Was there something else?
No, thank you.
Mr. Takagi chose his people well, Mrs. Gennaro.
Miss Gennaro.
We interrupt this program for a special news bulletin.
This is Richard Thornburg live from Century City.
Tonight, Los Angeles has joined the sad and worldwide fraternity of cities whose only membership requirement is to suffer the anguish of international terrorism.
Approximately two hours ago, an unidentified group of men seized control of the Nakatomi building, sealing off all entrances and exits.
All telephone lines have been cut.
And the only communication now possible has been through the use of CB communicators, which the group apparently brought with them.
Unit 5, hold your position at the main entrance.
All right, guys, this is what we got.
We got Charlie Unit in position by the parking structure.
We're going to send them in through the parking structure.
Let me ask you something.
Does this stairway go up through the escalator?
Yeah, that's where they're going.
They're going to go through the lobby up there and try and draw some fire.
What's going on?
What's it look like?
It's going in.
Going in?
Man, that's crazy.
There could be over 30 hostages in there for all we know.
We don't know shit, pal.
If there's hostages, how come nobody's come to us with ransom demands, huh?
If there's terrorists in there, where's their list of demands?
All we know is that somebody shot your car up.
It's probably the same silly son of a bitch you've been talking to on that radio.
Excuse me, sir.
But what about the body that fell out the window?
Well, who knows?
It's probably some stockbroker.
Got depressed.
We're ready for you, Chief.
All right, light them up.
Let's go.
All right, hit your lights.
We got approval, Chief.
Yeah.
Al.
Al, you still with me, babe?
What's going on?
Yo, Al.
I'm here, Roy.
But I'm kind of busy right now.
I'll talk to you later.
Al, what's wrong?
What's going on?
I said I'll talk to you later, Roy.
If you are what I think you are, then you'll know when to listen, when to shut up, and when to pray.
Jesus Christ, you're coming in.
That's it, isn't it?
Christ, pal, I told you what kind of people you're dealing with here.
All right, let's load them up.
Blue go.
Sir.
They'll be coming.
Everyone get ready.
Theo, you are the eyes now.
Rivers, you begin your reconnoiter.
Hey!
Shut up.
Let's go.
Macho assholes.
No, no!
All right.
Listen up, guys.
It was the night before Christmas, and all through the house, not a creature was stirring, except the four assholes coming in the rear in standard two by two cover formation.
OK, we're all set.
We're ready.
Kick ass.
Go!
Right.
Let's do it.
They're shooting at them.
It's panic fire.
They can't see anything.
They're shooting at the lights.
They're going after the lights.
Call them back.
It's not happening.
Mike, burn it.
Don't be impatient.
Just wound them.
Get them back.
They're sitting ducks up there.
No, no, they're almost in.
Get them back.
Almost in.
Send in the car.
Rogers, Rodriguez, report.
Whoa, wait a minute, wait a minute.
What have we here, gentlemen?
The police have themselves an RV.
Southeast corner.
You fool, idiot!
Jesus Christ!
I don't care!
Get back!
Get the fuck back!
Get over there!
Schnell, schnell!
Ach, scheie!
Lass liegen!
Weiter, weiter, weiter!
Oh, langsam.
I see him!
Oh, yeah!
Yeah!
Oh, my God!
The quarterback is toast!
All right, all right, all right!
Let's go!
Hang on, Rivers.
That's an order.
Hit it again.
Aren't you, motherfucker?
You made your point.
Let him pull back.
Thank you, Mr. Cowboy.
I'll take it under advisement.
Hit it again.
Let's go.
Get him out of the car.
We're going to get you.
Fuck it.
So you take this under advisement, jerkweed.
Shit!
They're using artillery on us.
You idiot.
It's not the police.
It's him.
Tell me you got that.
I got it.
I hit your heart out, Channel 5.
We've had an update on the terrorist takeover of the Nakatomi building.
Sources say the terrorist leader Hans may be this man Hans Gruber, a member of the radical West German Volksfrei movement.
Strangely, the Volksfrei leadership issued a communique an hour ago stating that Gruber had been expelled from that organization.
Al, Al, do you copy?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
What was that?
Remember that plastic explosive I told you about?
Yeah.
There you go.
Is the building on fire?
No, but it's going to need a paint job and a shitload of screen doors.
Our spotters say you got two with that blast.
Is that him?
Yes, sir.
Now, you listen to me, mister.
I don't know who the hell you think you are or what you're doing, but you just destroyed a building.
Now, we do not want your help.
Is that clear?
We don't want your help.
I've got 100 people down here, and they're covered with glass.
Glass?
Who gives a shit about glass?
Who the fuck is this?
This is Deputy Chief of Police Dwayne T. Robinson, and I am in charge of this situation.
Oh, you're in charge.
Well, I got some bad news for you, Dwayne.
From up here, it doesn't look like you're in charge of jack shit.
You listen to me, you little asshole.
I'm gonna- Asshole?
I'm not the one who just got buttfucked on national TV, Dwayne.
Now you listen to me, Jerkoff.
If you're not part of the solution, you're part of the problem.
Quit being part of the fucking problem and put the other guy back on.
Hey, Roy, how you feeling?
Pretty fucking unappreciated, Al.
Hey, look, I love you.
So do a lot of the other guys.
So you hang in there, man.
You hear me?
You hang in there.
Yeah, thanks, partner.
What are you doing?
Tired of sitting here, waiting to see who gets us killed first, them or your husband.
What are you going to do?
Hey, babe, I negotiate million dollar deals for breakfast.
I think I can handle this euro trash.
Hey, frequency talk, huh?
If you listen to me, he would be neutralized already.
I don't want neutral.
I want dead.
Hope I'm not interrupting.
What does he want?
It's not what I want, it's what I can give you.
Look, let's be straight, okay?
It's obvious you're not some dumb schmuck up here to snatch a few purses, am I right?
You're very perceptive.
I watch 60 Minutes.
I say to myself, these guys are professional.
They're motivated.
They're happening, i.e., they want something, huh?
Now, personally, I couldn't care less about your politics.
Maybe you're pissed off at the Camel jockeys.
Maybe it's the Hebes, Northern Ireland.
It's none of my business.
I figure you're here to negotiate.
Am I right?
You're amazing.
You figured this all out already.
Hey.
Business is business.
You use a gun, I use a fountain pen.
What's the difference?
Let's put it in my terms.
You're here in a hostile takeover.
You grab us for some green mail, but you didn't expect some poison pill was going to be running around in the building.
Am I right?
Hans, Bobby, I'm your white knight.
I must have missed 60 minutes.
What are you saying?
The guy upstairs is fucking things up, huh?
I can give them to you.
Oh, God.
Roy.
Roy, you all right?
I was trying to fire that 1,000-year-old twinkie.
What do they put in these things, anyway?
Sugar-enriched flour, partially hydrogenated vegetable oil, polysorbate 60, and yellow dye number five.
Just everything a growing boy needs.
How many kids you got, Al?
Well, as a matter of fact, my wife is working on our first.
How about you, cowboy?
You got any kids back on your ranch?
Yeah, two.
I sure hope I can see him swinging on a jungle gym with Al Junior someday.
Well, now, that's a date.
But you're going to have to bring the ice cream.
Touching, cowboy, touching.
Mr. McClain.
Mr. Officer John McClain of the New York Police Department.
Get on the phone to Harry in New York.
Come on, baby, move.
Got it.
You better get hold of somebody at dispatch.
Sister Teresa called me Mr. McClain in the third grade.
My friends call me John.
You're neither, shithead.
I have someone who wants to talk to you.
A very special friend who was with you at the party tonight.
Hey, John boy.
Ellis?
Yeah.
Now, listen, John.
Give me a few minutes to try to talk some sense into you.
I know you think you're doing your job, John, and I can appreciate that, but you're just dragging this thing out.
Now, look.
No one gets out of here until these guys can talk to the LA police.
And that just ain't going to happen until you stop messing up the works.
Capisce?
Ellis, what have you told them?
I told them we were old friends and you were my guest at the party.
Ellis, you shouldn't be doing this.
Tell me about it, huh?
All right, John, listen.
They want you to tell them where the detonators are.
They know people are listening.
They want the detonators or they're going to kill me.
John, didn't you hear me?
Yeah, I hear you.
Hey, John, I think you could get with the program a little, huh?
The police are here now.
It's their problem.
Now, tell these guys where the detonators are so no one else gets hurt.
You know, I'm putting my life on the line for you, pal.
Ellis, listen to me very carefully.
John.
Shut up, Ellis.
Just shut your mouth.
Put Hans back on the line.
Hans, this shithead does not know what kind of man you are, but I do.
Listen.
Good.
Then you'll give us what we want and save your friend's life.
You're not part of this equation.
It's time you realized that.
Hey, what am I, method actor Hans?
Babe, put away the gun.
This is radio, not television.
Hans, this asshole is not my friend.
I just met him tonight.
I don't know him.
Jesus Christ, Ellis, these people are gonna kill you.
Tell them you don't know me.
John, how can you say that after all these years, huh?
John.
You hear that?
Talk to me.
Where are my detonators?
Where are they, or shall I shoot another one?
Sooner or later, I might get to someone you do care about.
Go fuck yourself, Hans.
Did you hear that?
He just let the guy die, man.
He just gave him up.
Give me that headset.
That's like pulling the trigger yourself.
Christ, man, can't you see what's happening?
Can't you read between the lines?
He did everything he could to save him.
If he gave himself up, they'd both be dead right now.
No way, man.
No way.
They'd be talking to us.
Listen, you tell this partner of yours, pal, to stay the hell out of this from now on.
Do you hear me?
Because if he doesn't, I'm going to nail him, boy.
I'm really going to nail his ass now.
Believe me.
The man is hurting.
He is alone, tired, and he hasn't seen diddly squat from anybody down here.
Are you going to stand there and tell me that he's going to give a damn about what you do to him if he makes it out of there alive?
Why don't you wake up and smell what you shoveling?
You listen to me, Sergeant.
Anytime you want to go home, you consider yourself dismissed.
No, sir.
You couldn't drag me away.
Attention, police.
This is Sergeant Al Power.
This is Deputy Chief Duane Robinson.
Who is this?
This is Hans Gruber.
I assume you realize the futility of direct action against me.
We have no wish for further loss of life.
Well, what is it you do wish for, Mr. Gruber?
I have comrades in arms around the world languishing in prison.
The American State Department enjoys rattling its saber for its own ends.
Now it can rattle it for me.
The following people are to be released from their captors.
In Northern Ireland, the seven members of the new Provo Front.
In Canada, the five imprisoned leaders of Libert de Qubec.
in Sri Lanka, the nine members of the Asian Dawn.
What the fuck?
I read about them in Time magazine.
When these revolutionary brothers and sisters are free, the hostages in this building will be taken to the roof, and they will accompany us in helicopters to the Los Angeles International Airport, where they will be given further instructions.
You have two hours to comply.
Wait a minute, Mr. Gruber.
This is crazy.
I don't have the authority.
I can't authorize.
Two hours is not enough.
Hello?
Danny, did you get all that?
Let's go.
We gotta make some calls.
Do you think they'll even try to do it?
Who cares?
Theo, are we on schedule?
One more to go, then it's up to you.
And you better be right, because it looks like this last one's gonna take a miracle.
It's Christmas, Theo.
It's the time of miracles.
So be of good cheer and call me when you hit the last lock.
Carl, hunt that little shit down and get those detonators.
Fritz is checking explosives.
I'll check the explosives.
You just get the detonators.
Hey, pal, you out there?
I'm here, John.
I'm here.
You gotta believe me.
There's nothing I could do.
Well, it's gonna be both our asses if you're wrong.
I hear you.
Did you catch that bullshit Hans was running?
Doesn't make sense, man.
Hey, don't ask me, man.
I'm just a desk jockey who was on my way home when you rang.
Well, you drove that car.
I figured you for the street, Al.
In my youth.
and author of Hostage Terrorist, Terrorist Hostage, A Study in Duality.
Dr. Hasseldorf, what can we expect in the next few hours?
Well, Gail, by this time, the hostages should be going through the early stages of the Helsinki Syndrome.
As in Helsinki, Sweden.
Finland.
Basically, it's when the hostages and the terrorists go through a sort of psychological transference and a projection of dependency.
A strange sort of trust and bond develops.
We've had situations where the hostages have embraced their captors after their release and even corresponded with them in prison.
No, no, no, darling.
Asian Dawn.
Dawn.
D-A-W-N.
Sir?
Yeah.
Sir, the FBI's here.
Oh.
The FBI is here now?
Yes, sir, right over there.
Pull this.
You want a breath, man?
Yeah, OK.
Hey, how you doing, man?
I'm Agent Johnson.
This is Special Agent Johnson.
Oh, how you doing?
No relation.
I'm, uh, I'm Dwayne Robinson, LAPD.
I'm in charge here.
Not anymore.
Hi there.
How you doing?
Oh.
Please, God, no.
You're one of them, aren't you?
You're one of them.
No, no.
Don't kill me.
Please, no, please.
Please, please, please.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Relax.
I'm not going to hurt you.
What the fuck are you doing up here?
What were you looking for?
I managed to get out of there.
Well, I was just trying to get up on the roof and see if I could signal for help, you know.
It's just right here.
Why don't you come in?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Forget the roof.
I said forget the roof.
I got people all over it.
Come on, you want to stay alive, you stay with me.
Well, the best way we can figure it is we've got maybe 30 or 35 hostages up there, probably on the 30th floor, and maybe, I don't know, seven or eight terrorists up there.
Sounds like an A7 scenario.
Thank you.
We'll handle it from here.
When we commandeer your men, we'll try and let you know.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Such as?
What about John McClane?
He's the reason why we have the information we have up until now.
He's also the reason why you're facing seven terrorists instead of 12.
He's inside?
Who is he?
Well, he might be a cop.
I don't know.
We're checking on that.
One of yours?
No.
No way.
You smoke?
Yeah.
You don't work for Nakatomi.
And if you're not one of them.
I'm a cop from New York.
New York?
Yeah.
Got invited to the Christmas party by mistake.
Who knew?
Yeah, it's better than being called your pants down, huh?
I'm John McClain.
You're, uh?
Clay.
Bill.
Now to use a handgun, Bill?
I spent a weekend at a combat ranch.
You know that game where the guns that shoot red paint?
Probably seems kind of stupid to you.
Well, time for the real thing, Bill.
All you got to do is pull the trigger.
Come on.
Put down the gun and give me my detonators.
Well, well, well.
Hans.
Put it down now.
It's pretty tricky with that accent.
You ought to be on fucking TV with that accent.
But what do you want with the detonators, Hans?
I already used all the explosives.
Or did I?
I'm going to count to three.
Yeah, like you did with Takagi.
Oops.
No bullets.
You think I'm fucking stupid, Hans?
You were saying?
Move!
Garland.
She's Stimfenster.
Shoot the glass.
That's my apparel.
We're back in business.
...is the last resort of diplomacy.
Then couldn't we just as well say that terrorism has an equal claim on being that, too?
You got something.
Tell me you got something.
Just McLean's name, badge number, employment record, vital statistics, and his family's home address.
Right here in L.A.
God, that man looks really pissed.
He's still alive.
What?
Only John can drive somebody that crazy.
Hans, you better heat up that miracle, because we just broke through on number six, and the electromagnetic came down like a fucking anvil.
Well, have a look at what our friends outside are doing, and I'll be right up.
Hey, John.
John McClane, you still with us?
Yeah.
But all things being equal, I'd rather be in Philadelphia.
Chalk up two more bad guys.
Well, the boys down here will be glad to hear that.
You know we got a pool going on you.
What kind of odds am I getting?
You don't want to know.
Pull me down for 20.
I'm good for it.
Hey, pal.
You got flat feet?
What the hell you talking about, man?
Something had to get you off the street.
What's the matter?
You don't think jockeying papers across a desk is a noble effort for a cop?
No.
I had an accident.
The way you drive, I can see why.
What'd you do?
Run over your captain's foot with the car.
I shot a kid.
He was 13 years old.
Oh, it was dark.
I couldn't see him.
He had a ray gun look real enough.
You know, when you're a rookie, they can teach you everything about being a cop except how to live with a mistake.
Anyway, I just couldn't bring myself to draw my gun on anybody again.
Sorry, man.
Hey, man.
How could you know?
I feel like shit anyway.
Well, then this won't matter.
The LAPD is not calling the shots down here anymore.
You got it.
All right, those are the city engineers.
Wait.
They're going into the street circuit.
And those guys in the suits, I don't know who they are.
That's the FBI.
They're ordering the others to cut the building's power.
Regular as clockwork.
Or a time lock.
Precisely.
The circuits that cannot be cut are cut automatically in response to a terrorist incident.
You asked for miracles, Theo.
I give you the FBI.
I said I want the friggin' building shut down.
I got a problem.
I don't care what your problem is.
I don't give two shits about your switch.
I want the building out.
Doc, D-A-R-K.
You don't understand.
You can't do it from here.
Yeah, you could.
It can't be done from here.
I could just, I got the ring.
We can't do it from down here, I'm telling you.
It's got to be done from downtown.
They've got to take out a whole city grid.
We're talking 10 square blocks.
10 blocks, Gene.
Johnson, that's crazy.
It's Christmas Eve, man.
There's thousands of people.
You have to go wider.
The mayor will have my ass.
Authorization?
How about the United States fucking government?
Hey, lose the grid or you lose your job.
Yeah, Central?
Yeah, this is Walt down at Nakatomi.
Say, listen, would it be possible for you to turn off Grid 212?
Maybe I should call the mayor on this.
Hey, no shit, it's my ass.
I got a big problem down here.
Shut it down.
Shut it down now.
Emergency lighting activated.
Al, Al, talk to me.
What's going on here?
Ask the FBI.
They got the universal terrorist playbook, and they're running it step by step.
It's going to go.
Merry Christmas.
Those bastards are probably pissing in their pants right now.
The mayor's gonna cut my ass.
Well, what are we going to do now?
Arrest them for not paying their electric bill?
We shut them down.
We let them sweat for a while.
Then we give them helicopters.
Right up the ass.
This is Agent Johnson.
No, the other one.
I want that air support ready to lift off in five minutes.
Damn right, fully armed.
We're on the way.
I wish to talk to the FBI.
This is Special Agent Johnson of the FBI.
The State Department has arranged for the return of your comrades.
Helicopters are en route as you requested.
I hear you.
We'll be ready.
By the time he figures out what hit him, he'll be in a body bag.
When they touch down, we'll blow the roof.
They'll spend a month sifting through the rubble, and by the time they figure out what went wrong, we'll be sitting on a beach earning 20%.
Pal.
Yo, pal, you got a minute?
I'm here, John.
Listen, man, I'm starting to get a bad feeling up here.
I want you to do something for me.
I want you to find my wife.
Don't ask me how.
By then, you'll know how.
I want you to tell her something.
I want you to tell her that it took me a while to figure out what a jerk I'd been.
that when things started to pan out for her, I should have been more supportive.
And I just should have been behind her more.
Oh, shit.
Tell her that, um,
That she is the best thing that ever happened to a bum like me.
She's heard me say I love you a thousand times.
She never heard me say I'm sorry.
And I want you to tell her that, Al.
I want you to tell her that John said that he was sorry.
OK?
You got that, man?
But you can tell her that yourself.
You just watch your ass and you'll make it out of there.
You hear me?
Well, I guess that's up to the man upstairs.
John?
What the fuck were you doing upstairs, Hans?
No, Al, listen.
Listen, just lay off for a while.
We gotta go check on something.
One minute.
That's all I'm asking.
One minute just to speak to them.
All right, all right, all right.
Get back, get back.
All right, all right.
Look, you let me in right now or I call the INS.
Comprende?
Look, this is the last time these kids are gonna have to speak to their parents.
All right?
All right.
How are you doing, hon?
How are you doing?
Listen to me.
It's a double cross.
The whole roof of the building's wired.
John.
John, come in.
Did you get that?
No.
It's something about a double cross.
Tell me about it.
We are both professionals.
This is personal.
They're coming.
The choppers are coming.
OK.
Time to gather your flock, Miss Gennaro.
You know your mom and dad are very important people.
They're very brave people.
So is there something you'd like to say to them, if they're watching?
Come home.
Mrs. McLane.
It's on us to make your acquaintance.
On your feet, everyone!
To the roof!
Lock them up there and come right back.
Come on, let's move!
I broke his fucking neck!
Where do you figure the breakage?
Figure we take out the terrorists, lose 20, 25% of the hostages.
Tops.
I can live with that.
Keep this thing on the deck.
They're expecting transports, not gunships.
Move!
My butt!
Move it!
Now!
Move!
Here.
A little bonus for us.
Please, sit down.
Sit down.
Hey!
A policeman's wife might come in handy.
McClane, I have some news for you.
McClane.
The truck?
The truck.
After all your posturing, all your little speeches, you're nothing but a common thief.
I am an exceptional thief, Mrs. McLane.
And since I'm moving up to kidnapping, you should be more polite.
I don't like this Sarge.
Yeah!
To slide fucking Saigon!
Hey Slick!
I was in junior high, dickhead.
Where's Holly Gennaro?
Holly Gennaro!
Where's Holly?
Where is she?
They took her!
Where?
The vault!
Where is the vault?
The 30th floor!
Up the stairs!
They just took her!
Get downstairs, all of you!
The whole fucking room is wired to blow!
Get down!
Get the fuck downstairs!
They made us, Bureau.
You got a terrorist shooter.
I see it!
Bank left!
I'm on your side, you assholes!
Shit.
Swing around again.
I'll bag this little bastard.
Oh, John, what the fuck are you doing?
How the fuck did you get into this shit?
There's something wrong.
They're coming back down.
Blow the roof.
The car's up there.
I promise I will never even think about going up in a tall building again.
Oh, god, please don't let me die.
Ah!
Oh, Christ.
Gonna need some more FBI guys, I guess.
What the fuck is going on?
What are you gonna do, sit here while a building falls down around your ears?
Shit!
All right!
Nali!
Hey!
Hans!
Jesus.
Hi, honey.
So that's what this is all about?
Fucking robbery?
Put down the gun.
Why'd you have to nuke the whole building, Hans?
Well, when you steal $600, you can just disappear.
When you steal $600 million, they will find you, unless they think you're already dead.
Put down the gun.
You got me.
Still the cowboy, Mr. McLane.
Americans all alike.
Well, this time John Wayne does not walk off into the sunset with Grace Kelly.
It was Gary Cooper, asshole.
Enough jokes.
You made a pretty good cowboy yourself, Hans.
Oh, yes.
What was it you said to me before?
Yippee-ki-yay, motherfucker.
Happy trails, Hans.
No!
Oh, I hope that's not a hostage.
Oh.
Okay, come on.
Come on, we're gonna lift it.
Okay, count in my notes.
Come on.
Keep that water on you, all right?
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
Everything's fine.
We're all good.
Thank you, Joe.
It's all good.
It's all right.
Yeah.
I don't know.
That was my wife, Holly.
Holly Gennaro.
Holly McClain.
Hello, Holly.
You got yourself a good man.
You take good care of him.
McClain?
McClain, I want a debrief.
I want a debriefing.
You got some things to answer for, mister.
Ellis' murder, for one thing, property damage, interfering with police business.
All right, Paul, the two of you, go inside, see if there's anybody else.
Yes, sir.
We'll take a left.
This was with me.
Mr. McClane, Mr. McClane, now that it's all over after this incredible ordeal, what are your feelings?
Merry Christmas, old pal.
Merry Christmas.
Did you get that?
This is their idea of Christmas.
I got to be here for New Year's.