The political situation in the world has now reached the stage where the very foundations of civilization are seriously threatened.
War is a contagion.
The peace of the world, the welfare and security of every nation, including our own, is being threatened by that very thing.
Let no one imagine that America will escape.
Yes, we are determined to keep out of war, yet we cannot insure ourselves against the disastrous effects of war and the dangers of involvement.
This is bloody ridiculous.
Wasn't your empire built on ridiculous traditions?
Don't defend them, Layton.
You might speak their language, but they still think you're a barbarian.
Be honest.
You won't miss this place when you're gone?
Oh, please.
The next time I see the little buggers, I hope it's through the sights of a 14-inch gun.
Omigoto desu, Kimura-san!
Gentlemen, on behalf of the British Empire, I wish to thank Admiral Yamamoto for this invitation.
May our nations work together to maintain peace on the seas.
Do you not like whisky?
I have the same question.
According to reliable sources, your glass is made of tea.
It's an old trick from China.
What else did you learn in Japan?
I'm just an officer of the Japanese Embassy.
Which is why I know that you must have an opinion.
I was once our neighbor at Washington.
After you went to Harvard.
Like you.
I thought there was value in studying a potential adversary.
There's a rumor that you told the Prime Minister that Japan can't win a war with the United States.
I said we couldn't win a long war.
There's another rumor that your life is in danger.
that the nationalists think you're too moderate and have targeted you for assassination.
Japan is at the crossroads.
We are emboldened by our invasion of China and eager to become a world power.
Yet we get 80% of our oil from your country.
If that supply is threatened, it will force us into drastic measures.
You want me to pass this information along to Washington?
Don't push us into a corner.
You must give those of us who are more reasonable a chance to carry the day.
Nobody wants a war.
Goodbye, Blade.
Goodbye.
Step it up, ladies!
Clear the flight, Jack.
Let's go.
Prepare to brace.
Why aren't you using the flaps, sir?
Because someday we might have to land with our flaps shut away.
So we might as well practice now.
Imagine how Ensign Hunt used to fly.
Which is why Ensign Hunt is now counting seagulls in San Diego when you're here with me.
Looks like we got hit in our fuel tank, too.
Please don't, sir.
This might save your life one day, Murray.
Engine's about to die.
What the hell is Bess doing?
He's out of the groove.
It looks like his engine cut out.
Is he in a stunt or is he in trouble?
I don't know, but it's gonna hit the first wire lock always.
Hop with that angle.
Why are we sideways?
To change speed so we don't put a hole in the deck.
Better not crash that damn plane.
Hang in there, kid.
We're almost home.
Freeze!
Are you trying to get court-martialed?
I had an electrical issue.
Could happen to anyone.
Hey, good job.
All right, it's not me you have to convince.
McCluskey's about ready to have your ass.
Then I'll take it upstairs to the old man.
He knows what's coming.
That's why we've been flying double-scouting missions this whole trip.
Going somewhere?
Yeah, they're sending the whole squadron into Pearl this morning.
I'll be drinking a beer on the beach with Roy by noon.
And I'm not coming?
No, McCluskey's holding back scouting six.
It's probably because you're such an asshole.
Ah, you're loving this, right?
Morning, sir.
Aircraft just spotted.
Hey, take it easy, young Miller.
He's having a tough morning.
It's my last day of sea duty, sir.
And I'm the only one from my radio class who hasn't crashed.
Don't worry, Miller.
I'm sure even Mr. Dickinson can fly you from here to Pearl without getting you wet.
Hey, me and Roy will pour a little beer out on the beach for you.
Well, you boys are taking your sweet time.
Chaplain's gonna be here any minute.
It's another hot one, sir.
Are you complaining, Sully?
No, sir.
I just can't help wondering why I have to set up chairs for church, even though I don't believe in God.
Well, that's because your only religion is chasing tail.
The Navy ain't gonna pay you for that.
Get the wounded below deck!
Everyone else, battle stations!
Get down!
Coming to church?
I have to go to the office.
Sunday.
You work too hard.
Layton residence.
I'll meet you outside.
Edwin, what's happening?
The Japanese are attacking us.
Did you reach the office?
No, the switchboard was jammed.
Son, get up!
Come on!
Get up!
Drive!
We gotta jump.
Go in that water, you're dead.
Sully!
You first, Sully.
I can't.
Wait.
You wanna live?
You get to that goddamn ship, you hear me?
What is it, sir?
Looks like Kosar artillery went stark mad.
Bet you somebody's gonna catch hell for it.
What the hell is going on?
Pearl is shooting at our guys, sir.
Maybe it isn't Pearl, but call Dickinson.
We had a transmission that he was under attack, and then nothing.
Sir.
Get this to the Admiral.
Ah!
Hurry up!
Here's the man who tried to warn us.
Is there any satisfaction to you, Layton?
You were right.
Sir, it's no satisfaction to me whatsoever.
Sir, where are they going?
Back to their carriers.
Drive out to the radio direction finder and report back to me.
Yes, sir.
Admiral Halsey on deck.
Pearl found something.
Intelligence managed to get a line of bearing on the attacking fleet.
But it's a bilateral reading.
The Japanese are either at 343 degrees or 163 degrees.
Oh, for Christ's sake.
Pearl is under attack and we don't even know if the bastards are north or south?
Army bombers also reported a possible ship sighting here.
We're gonna place our bet.
Break there.
We have a possible location on the JAB fleet.
Fly a grid on bearing 185.
If you make contact, Best and his men will put down a smoke screen and then the torpedo bombers will make their runs.
Lindsey has command.
Hell with smoke.
Let me go after those carriers with a real bomb.
Torpedoes sink ships, not bombs, and my men need a screen.
Yeah, even if you get close enough, your torpedoes don't work.
That's a rumor.
Yeah, it's a rumor because the damn things have never been tested.
Look, the Jap's out there killing our friends.
Let me put a 500-pound bomb right down their goddamn smokestack.
We're not changing tactics just because you want revenge.
Going after the Japs, sir?
Yeah, we're gonna smoke them to death.
Japanese are attacking on multiple fronts.
We captured a radio log from a downed Japanese plane.
They hit us with all six of their fleet carriers.
At least they didn't destroy our oil tanks.
The whole fleet would have had to withdraw to the west coast.
You are the best intelligence officer I've ever known, Layton.
I'll probably burn you for this, too.
But if they don't, swear to me, we'll make the next man in this chair listen to you.
Anything, sir?
Not even a goddamn whale.
Six Baker 10.
Six Torpedo 1.
Lead us back to Enterprise.
Six Torpedo 1, your pilots aren't trained for a night carrier landing with live ordnance.
Go land at Pearl.
We can't clear the mountains.
Take us back to Enterprise, Lieutenant.
That's an order, Lieutenant.
I'm dropping my smoke tanks and returning to Enterprise.
Follow me if you want.
We got word from Pearl.
Cap fleet was north, not south.
God damn it.
Hey, Lindsey, this is what I was afraid of.
One of your men almost blows up the damn carrier because you were too afraid to get shot down flying in a Pearl.
Do I have to remind you that I am your superior officer, Lieutenant?
You gonna hide behind your rank?
Save it for the Japs.
We're at war now, McCluskey.
When that guy screws up, people die.
Listen to me.
You want to keep playing?
I suggest you knock off the cowboy bullshit.
Come on, Murray.
Jesus.
What are they doing?
When she went over, everyone below deck was probably trapped inside.
Did you know anyone aboard Arizona?
Yeah.
My roommate from the Academy.
Lieutenant Roy Pierce.
Heard you jumped out of a perfectly good plane.
Well, it was on fire, and the controls were dead.
Where's Miller?
Oh, hell.
Yeah.
Hey, Ann's by the gate.
You OK?
Yeah, I'm all right.
Come home tonight.
I wish.
We sail as soon as we're refueled.
Look, I want you and Barb to go back to your parents' place in Jersey.
No.
It's not safe.
Everyone is saying this is gonna be a long war.
What if... You're not shipping us off to Jersey.
And that's final.
You talked to Sarah?
It was royal board to Arizona.
Yes.
We're checking all the hospitals, but nothing yet.
Tell her I'll find him.
Thank you.
Hey.
I heard you were with Lieutenant Pierce during the attack.
Sully, what happened to him?
I don't know.
We're doing our best.
They've been bringing body parts and pillowcases.
There's too many.
He was a blond guy, tall, probably wearing an officer's uniform.
Officer's down here.
Is there anything else you can give me?
And find features, tattoos?
Well, he would have been wearing our class ring from Annapolis.
We took this off the body when he came in.
I'm sorry.
I'll give you a moment.
December 7, 1941, a day which will live in infamy.
The United States of America was suddenly and deliberately attacked by naval and air forces of the Empire of Japan.
The United States was at peace with that nation.
And at the solicitation of the time, was still in conversation with its government and its... What happened?
I woke up the sleeping titan and made a terrible decision.
Did you have fun in Hawaii?
We found a battleship in Nagumo and decided to destroy the fuel tank.
But it was rejected.
It's a terrible mistake.
If we attack, the U.S.
Army won't be able to resume its military operations in Shinjuan in the next year.
When will Nagumo be removed from the commander's office?
Nagumo sank an American battleship.
Everyone thinks he's a hero.
He'll make bigger mistakes in the future.
Don't talk about it.
It's important to fight the army.
I'm not Nagumo.
Shinjuan was a great victory.
But...
Congratulations, sir.
You're the right man to run the Navy.
When they get in trouble, they send for the sons of bitches.
At this point, our priority is to expand our supply of resources, which is essential for the Great Japanese Empire.
That is the task of the Army, and the Navy's task is to send the Army to the ground and bring them back.
The situation in the Pacific is far worse than has been reported.
We have three carriers.
The Japs have ten.
We have zero functional battleships.
They have nine.
They have more cruisers, more bombers, more fighters, and much of their equipment is more modern.
We'll just have to count on the men that we have out there to hold the line.
I don't envy the new commander.
It's me, isn't it?
The president asked for you himself.
He said that... ...you should get the hell out to Pearl and stay there... ...until our ships sail into Tokyo Bay.
Welcome to the most difficult job in the world.
The U.S.
Army got us involved in the war, and now you're asking for help?
That's right.
But the situation hasn't changed.
I want you to start planning the operation we talked about the other day.
Midway, right?
I'm so sorry.
Roy wanted to be a pilot like you.
But I talked him out of it.
I said it was too dangerous.
I'll see you at the next funeral.
You don't have to go.
Yes, I do.
We're family.
Hey, hey!
I just want to say, Roy Pearce is one of the finest bastards.
that I've ever met, and I could talk about the man for an hour, but I think that's a job to leave up to one of you boys that went to the academy with him.
What do you say?
Well, I can't let some torpedo jockey speak for Roy, especially one not good enough to fly from Enterprise.
Hey.
That summer after plebe year, me, Roy, and Dickie went up to visit Roy's uncle up in the Great Lakes.
There's the peak of prohibition, so one night we decide to sail to Canada to buy a keg of beer.
On our way back, right before the sun comes up, the wind dies.
So there we are, just floating in the middle of the lake, waiting for the border patrol to show up.
I said we should just ditch the booze, but Roy... Hey, Dickie, what did Roy say?
Hell no.
We'll drink it all.
Roy was my best man.
He was the godfather to my daughter.
I thought someday we'd be on a porch drinking beers, telling lies about what we did in the big war.
To Roy.
Man, oh, man.
Why'd you make me drink so much?
You might have to carry me home, darling.
Ah, shit, shore patrol.
That's the admiral's flag.
I bet it's the new commander.
Who do you think it is?
Looks like Nimitz.
I hear he's true.
Look.
Hey, Nimitz!
When you gonna let us hit those Japs?
I'm sorry, sir.
Do you want me to get their names?
No.
I think he may have heard you.
I'm glad at least some of the boys still wanna fight.
Welcome to Pearl, sir.
I'm Lieutenant Commander Layton.
I know who you are.
Well, then you'll understand my request.
I wish to be reassigned to a destroyer.
Didn't you try to warn my predecessor about the impending attack?
Well, not exactly.
I said that we had lost track of the enemy carriers and needed to be prepared.
I should have pushed harder.
A lesson I assume you have taken to heart.
Sir, I'm the intelligence officer responsible for overseeing the greatest intelligence failure in American history.
Close the door.
Morale is at an all-time low, and for good reason.
The Japanese are advancing on all fronts at a terrifying pace.
I nevertheless know the fighting spirit of our men.
And I have faith in them.
But I also need to know that they have faith in themselves.
I need you to be my Admiral Yamamoto.
Get in his head.
Tell me what he's gonna do next.
Your first assignment.
We need to throw a punch.
Not just for morale, but so the Japanese know what it feels like to be hit.
I'm sending Halsey to attack the Marshall Islands, but I need to know that they're not walking into a trap.
Target is Roy Island.
Our submarines have reported shipping traffic and one military airfield.
We don't know what we're facing, so hit them as hard as possible and then get the hell out.
So what about the enemy carrier?
Intelligence says they're 2,000 miles away.
You mean the same group of geniuses who didn't know the Japs were down at Fort Pearl?
Like I said, be prepared for anything.
We're gonna hit that anchorage before the Japs have even ruled out a bet.
Looks like he spit-polished his shoes.
Hey, guys, let's get home in one piece.
Oh, don't you worry.
What's the plan, sir?
The other squadrons will strike first.
Then we go in and clean up the remaining targets.
The Jets will know we're coming.
What happens if we get shot down?
I'm not gonna end up as a POW.
Neither are you.
Start to run, boys!
Engage torpedoes!
Like our boys on Roy booked a hornet's nest.
We got a problem.
I got eyes on a second enemy airfield on Taroa Island.
I'm counting maybe 30 bombers and heavy fighter cover.
You hear that, boys?
If we don't knock out that airfield, they'll go after Enterprise.
And I want to place the land when this is over.
Let's get out of here, Murray.
Yeah, we got most of the bombers, but not all of them.
Looks like they almost got you.
Yeah, not enough left.
What, too much excitement for you?
I'm not looking to win a medal.
You know the Navy's gonna make you pay for this aircraft.
And how'd you boys do?
We lost Hopping.
He never pulled out of his dive.
That can't be good.
Two-engine bombers, five o'clock.
Goddamn gunners, don't they know they gotta lead those...
What the hell is he doing?
He's turning himself into a bomb.
Damn, Bruno.
Weren't they planning this to kill Jets?
Admiral Halsey wants to see you.
That's the bravest damn thing I think I've ever seen.
What's your name, son?
Bruno Guido, sir.
Aviation machinist mate, third class.
Well, Bruno, you're now an aviation machinist mate, first class.
Signal the fleet.
Tell them it's time to haul ass with Halsey.
Yes, sir.
You heard the man.
Signal the fleet.
Are you really sure you want your wife flying wingmen for you tonight?
Yeah, nobody told me there'd be USO girls here tonight.
Hey.
Hi.
I got us a table?
Wade, have you met Ann?
Wade McCluskey.
I fly with your husband.
Hey, uh, you want a drink?
I do, if you want me to dance.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
How long have you been married?
Long enough to know my husband's talents.
Why isn't he commanding a squadron?
Well, I don't make those decisions.
Two white times, please.
Yes, sir.
I understand before the war when it was about politics, but now?
I told you she was a firecracker.
I have to say, I often wondered what kind of woman would marry Dick Best.
Well, you have not disappointed.
Dick Best.
Hey, ladies.
Hey.
How was the Marshall Islands?
Eh, we got our feet wet.
You keeping tabs on me?
I'm with Fleet Intelligence.
Thank God.
We're gonna need someone as smart as you after Pearl.
You gonna straighten those boys out?
I'll do my best.
You're my day, sir.
Well, I'm rooting for you.
Hey, say hi to the wife.
You as well.
Just be straight with me.
What am I missing?
Every time we go up in one of those planes, there's a chance we won't come back.
Now it's hard to follow a man who doesn't know that.
Or even worse, doesn't care.
Let's dance.
Hey, excuse me.
or nothing at all never appear to me if your heart never could yield to me
Welcome aboard Enterprise.
You're replacing good men.
Much earlier than me or the Navy wanted, but... Well, that's the hand we've been dealt.
Now you're going into rotation, and as XO, it's my job to make sure you're worth more than a bucket of warm spit.
The Japs are waiting for us, so we need pilots who can hold their own.
Hey.
You gotta see this.
Well, Mr. Browning, the commander of those bombers, Lieutenant Colonel James Doolittle, may be the best pilot in the world, and he intends to launch his planes off the Hornet, strike Tokyo, and then land in Free China.
Captain?
Enemy picket's 50 miles out.
They're gonna blow our cover.
Every mile we get Doolittle closer to Japan is fuel he'd use to get the hell out of there.
But I'm not gonna risk these carriers.
What do we tell Dulu?
The truth.
We got the order to launch.
How far out are we?
Too far.
We'll probably end up ditching in the East China Sea.
But if we bomb Tokyo,
We'll be the first enemy in Japan's history to hit their home territory.
If any of you want to bow out, now's your chance.
We all want to fly, sir.
Man your planes.
I'll see you all in China.
They can't take off.
Certainly not with the load, and they sure as hell can't land.
Ten bucks says they don't make it off the deck.
Yeah, I'll take that bet.
Evening, gents.
What's going on, Captain?
You sound like air raid sirens to me.
Your Majesty, I'm taking you to the airport.
Taking these hostage.
Just half an hour.
Does America winning the war really depend on Edwin Layton working himself to death?
Some of our boys bombed Tokyo today.
They were supposed to land in free China, but they're probably going to run out of fuel and have to ditch in the China Sea.
If by some miracle they actually make it into Japanese-occupied territory, they'll be tortured and executed.
What can you do?
Most likely nothing.
But we're not gonna lose any more men because I didn't dig deep enough.
I'll fix you a sandwich.
Steady tailwind!
You think we're over land?
Yeah!
I don't know if we're over Chinese or Jap territory.
Watch yourselves.
I'll see you all in Kuzu.
Excuse me.
Leave him alone.
Please come out of your room.
We exposed His Majesty's life in danger.
There were only a few enemy aircraft.
We promised to protect the main road.
Everyone thinks the US aircraft carrier was the right target.
We have to destroy it.
Commander Tojo is telling us to carry out Operation 35.
But after that, we need to be careful of Midway.
You have a train station.
Smoke comes out of the train.
I'm a friend.
American.
I'm an ally.
I need to get to Kuzo.
Kuzo.
Hello.
My name is Zhu Xuesheng, a school teacher.
You are American?
American.
I bombed Japan yesterday.
Where's the plane?
It crashed.
I bailed out and landed in the water last night.
Where's the parachute?
I left it at the shore.
Ask them.
I knocked on their door in the middle of the night.
He said he didn't know anything.
You're lying!
He say, you lie.
He want your gun.
I'm an American officer.
I keep my gun.
You bomb Japan?
I sure did.
Welcome.
Welcome!
I need to get the kudzu.
The Japanese are sending their carriers into the Coral Sea.
Yes, sir.
They're trying to break our lifeline with Australia.
Send a secure message to Admiral Halsey.
I want Enterprise to join Yorktown and Lexington in the Coral Sea.
And tell Halsey time is a factor.
There's something else.
There always is.
I heard a theory.
What kind of theory?
According to one of my officers, Coral Sea is just a warm-up.
He thinks that the Japanese are planning something bigger.
Much bigger.
What makes him think that?
Little bits and pieces that we've intercepted.
A message about a battleship not being ready for an upcoming operation.
A request for maps of the Aleutian Islands.
What's the target?
We don't know yet.
Do you trust this officer?
He's the most brilliant man I know.
Well, have him figure it out.
Always.
No match.
There are no installations here.
What's their target?
People are our target.
April... ...and we just made it worse.
I... I have to go.
My... family... ...they... they take you to Zhou... ...help find your man.
Thank you... ...for everything.
24 hours too late.
Damn it, why couldn't we have been here?
This leaves us and Hornet as the only carriers in the Pacific.
Attention on deck!
I want to talk to McCluskey and Best.
As you were.
Oh, for Christ's sake.
You okay, Admiral?
Got this damn rash.
Listen up.
I'm done playing politics.
The Navy, hell, the whole damn country is counting on us, and I need my best men in the right spots.
So, McCluskey, you are now in charge of the air group.
I don't have a lick of confidence in those damn torpedoes, so I want you in a dive bomber.
Best, I'm bumping you up from XO.
You're the new skipper of Bombing Six.
Good luck, boys.
Well, I guess you're gonna have to learn to fly an SPD.
I've logged plenty of hours in the Dauntless.
Not diving on a live target.
Can't be that hard.
I mean, you do it.
Lieutenant Dagmo, can you practice on the ground with that?
These young officers are ignoring the war.
I followed the Director's plan, and at the same time as the U.S.
Army fired from Shinchuan, they passed through our airspace.
So,
The U.S.
troops didn't come from Shenzhen, but from the northeast of Midway.
As the mobile force attacked Midway, the U.S.
troops took three scuba boats.
Unless the U.S.
troops read our operation code, they wouldn't be able to attack us.
We started over.
But this time,
So I just got off the phone with Washington and their intelligence guys think you're wrong about this big operation.
They think that the Japs are sending their carriers back into the Coral Sea.
Yeah, and they've ordered me to keep Enterprise down there.
That's a mistake.
Washington is starting from a faulty assumption and looking for evidence to corroborate it.
So what's the Japs' real target?
We believe it's midway.
They see our base there as a step towards Hawaii and eventually the West Coast.
When?
In a few weeks.
I think it's time to pay a visit to your friend's distinction hypo.
Matt, bring the car around.
I have to warn you, sir, code breakers are a rare breed.
Rochefort's way of doing things is especially particular.
I don't care if he consults coffee grounds while doing the boogie woogie as long as the intel is good.
Attention on deck.
Carry on, gentlemen.
Where's Rochefort?
If you'll follow me, sir.
I didn't realize that the Navy had so many trained codebreakers.
We don't.
Most of these men were in the band on the California.
But since we don't have much use for bands these days, Rochefort thought that their musical abilities might make them naturals at breaking the rhythms of cyphers.
Sorry, Admiral, it gets cold down here in the dungeon.
I'm told you're brilliant.
Well, Lieutenant Commander Layton's been known to exaggerate.
I hope not.
He told me he's absolutely certain the Japs are gonna hit Midway, and I need to know whether or not I can believe him.
Well, if you don't believe him, we'll all be speaking Japanese.
Or most likely we'll be dead.
Show me how this works.
You mean like a tour?
Exactly.
Like a tour.
So this is where it starts.
We intercept roughly 60% of secure Japanese radio traffic, and we've cracked enough of their code to be able to break about 40% of those messages.
So we're able to read about a quarter of their secure communications?
Uh, no, not exactly.
Uh, here's some of our, uh, cracked messages.
That's gibberish to me.
Yes, but if you read enough of it... Rochford has a gift for assembling the fragments.
He can recall a message from two months ago and plug it into today's intercept.
Explain the disagreement with Washington.
Well, we all have access to the same raw information, but over here is where our paths diverge.
Translation and analysis.
Washington agrees with us that Japs are going to attack a major target codenamed AF.
But Washington believes that AF is located in the South Pacific, which is why they ordered you to keep Enterprise down there.
Do you have any direct proof that they're wrong?
Direct proof, no, but... Sir, imagine that you're throwing a wedding.
And maybe I've never seen the invitation, but I hear from the caterers that they have an event on a certain date.
The flower guys buying up all the roses on the island.
The best band is booked.
That's what signal intelligence can give you.
Clues, not a definitive answer.
Sir, after Pearl, you told me to stick to my guns.
I swear to you, Joe's right about this.
I'm not generally predisposed to trust a bunch of tuba players led by a man wearing fuzzy slippers, but I'll figure a way to get the Enterprise back here.
Meantime, you gentlemen need to convince Washington
that the Japs' real target is Midway.
How, sir?
Washington doesn't exactly have a habit of listening to us.
Well, I'm sure you'll think of something.
Come in.
Nye's only message from Pearl.
Nimitz, he wants us to be spotted.
Because if the Japs see us, we can break our standing orders with Washington and return to Pearl.
We never received this message.
Sir?
Yeah?
The Admiral needs you.
Okay.
Yeah.
Well, keep me informed.
That was Washington.
They've intercepted several Japanese messages claiming that the target of their upcoming attack is out of fresh water.
Interesting, sir.
I heard that Midway accidentally sent out an unencrypted transmission that their water plant was broken.
And is their water plant broken?
Not that I know of, sir.
But that proves Midway is AF.
Okay, tell your man Rochefort that everyone now agrees on where his wedding is gonna be held.
We just need to know how many guests are coming and when they plan to arrive.
Mac, I think we found the spot.
Can't say, Mr. Ford, that I've ever helped a big-time Hollywood director scout for a movie before.
What kind of film are you planning to make in a godforsaken place like this?
A friend of mine in the Navy said that I might be able to find some real action here.
I think I've been hoodwinked.
I don't know, sir.
From the way we've been fortifying this little island, I'd say your friend has some good intel.
Attention on deck!
Very funny.
Sit the hell down.
I'm gonna keep this short.
I know some of you thought I was a pain in the ass as XO, but my head's about to get worse.
We're headed back to Pearl to resupply, and probably because something big is coming down the pipe.
I'm therefore doubling our scouting flights, and I expect you to practice diving runs whenever you get a chance.
Don't be the man who lets down the squadron when we finally face the Japs.
Dismissed.
Can I talk to you, sir?
I don't know if I can do this, sir.
I thought I was a good pilot, but... I've lost my confidence.
Why did you become a pilot?
Well, your dad wanted you to be an officer, huh?
Actually, my dad didn't have much respect for officers.
Said that most of them didn't know their ass from their elbow.
You know, my dad was a tough son of a bitch.
You know, I got his respect by always staying in the fight.
I wish I had the luxury of worrying about your confidence, but we're short on pilots, so you gotta suck it up.
Yes, sir.
Wait.
From now on, you're my wingman.
I'll be looking out for you.
Now go suit up for a scouting flight.
Tell me.
What's your secret?
My secret?
You must know why nothing bothers you.
My uncle was a welder on the Empire State Building.
You walk on a beam 1,000 feet up in the sky, no ropes, nothing.
You know, and everyone thought he was crazy, but the enemy was just doing the job.
And one Sunday, walking home from church, just a block away from his house, when a cab jumps over the curb, splatters him like a bug.
You never know what's gonna get you, so why worry about it?
Hey, let's go.
Simple scout mission.
On the way home, we practice a dive.
You got it?
Yes, sir.
And we'll be going deeper this time, so don't pull up too fast to the bottom, or you'll black out.
The ship's too slow!
We're not generating enough wind for launch!
No, stop!
Stop!
Plane in water!
Turn starboard, goddammit!
Turn starboard!
Guess you don't like the chokers either.
I get grease on that thing just trying to button it up.
Makes me look like a damn waiter.
Nobody would ever confuse you for a waiter.
You look like hell, Bill.
I'm fine.
Tired.
Every man on this ship's tired.
I've been out six months without a break.
There's a big difference between tired and whatever the hell you are.
You're going ashore to the hospital.
Does this look like a battle wound to you?
It's a damn rash.
Now, what are my men gonna think when their admiral up and decides he needs a vacation?
It's a direct order, Bill.
And we keep losing men.
It's not even the Japs.
Her name crashed on takeoff.
Tom Durkin disappeared on patrol.
And there's this other kid.
Willie West.
He didn't think he could cut it.
I figured it was just the usual jitters.
I take him under my wing.
I wrote a letter to his mother yesterday, telling her I failed him.
It's not your fault.
He was right to be scared.
Everybody knows something big is coming.
We're talking about a couple dozen planes against a whole Japanese fleet.
And if we lose, they own the Pacific.
And they raid the West Coast.
Seattle, San Francisco, Los Angeles.
Burn.
And this damn war will last a decade.
I've never seen you this worried before.
I never had to worry when it was just me and my plane.
It's different now.
I have to lead these men.
What do I say to them?
Just be honest.
Let them see what I can see.
Sir, the Yorktown was hit by a 500-pound bomb.
We need at least two weeks for repairs.
Not acceptable.
Our initial estimate was three months of dry dock in Seattle.
I need this ship.
I don't care if you need to patch the deck with plywood.
Yorktown sails in 72 hours.
Halsey is out.
He's in the hospital with shingles.
So I have given command of Task Force 16 to Admiral Spruance.
We're setting a trap.
Our carriers will lie in wait northeast of Medway.
Now, we have set up a picket line of submarines here.
As for Medway itself, we have crammed every plane we can spare onto that runway.
But this time, if we're lucky, surprise will be on our side.
Layton, how reliable are these estimates of the Japanese positions?
They represent our best guess, based on the intelligence that we have.
I can't plan around your guess.
I understand that we're asking the impossible, but we need you to be specific.
The Japanese will attack on the morning of June 4th from the northwest at a bearing of 325 degrees.
They will be sighted 175 miles from Midway at 0700 local time.
I trust Layton and his team.
Make your plans accordingly.
Dismissed.
Clear it in.
Torpedo Squadron six, target confirmed.
Easy, easy, easy.
Easy, boys, easy.
Get him over.
Head off.
One, two, three, up.
Easy, easy.
How's your back doing?
It feels like someone dropped a tractor on it.
So that's what your squadrons are up against.
Four carriers, approximately 250 aircraft, plus the biggest battleship in the world.
Yeah, not to mention the Japs are unbeatable.
We've got the drop on the bastards.
Make it count.
How's Lindsey?
Not good, sir.
You trust the intelligence?
I'm trying, because we're betting a hell of a lot on this hand.
Yeah.
I can't believe I'm saying this, but, uh...
Oh, really?
You've been blaming yourself for that kid who went down.
How do I make it right?
Make sure your men are ready for tomorrow.
And you bring back as many of them as you can.
Ship sighted.
How the hell did she get out of dry dock in time?
I don't know.
I guess every battle needs a miracle.
You've memorized every position on that board, Layton.
Go home.
I think I'm going to spend the night here, sir.
Just in case anything comes up.
Your wife doesn't mind.
Well, she knows the drill.
My wife knows the drill too, but she still minds.
And when the war's over, I plan on spending the rest of my life making it up to her.
Some rest.
Good night.
They scrambled all the squadrons.
Radar must have picked up something.
That's great, Mike.
That's great.
Next time, get the horn up a little higher.
Right?
A little higher.
Good.
All right, lower the flag.
We're going again.
There's something in your stomachs.
And it's going to be a long day.
I'm not gonna sugarcoat it, boys.
Nobody thinks we can go toe-to-toe with the Japanese.
Not in a fair fight.
Today we're gonna be big underdogs.
Me?
I think the men in this room can fly with anyone.
Maybe that's because I'm a cocky son of a bitch.
But it's also because I've seen what you can do.
You're ready for this.
We're gonna give him a shellackin'.
Incoming aircraft.
We need to get you to a bunker.
Incoming aircraft?
Sir, you have to take cover, sir.
Holy shit!
To the ropes!
Mr. Ford, wait!
With all due respect, sir, this isn't gonna be a movie, sir, if we don't get you to cover.
I'm gonna shoot the damn picture!
Got it, Jagger?
Japanese air attack reported on Midway, and one of our scout planes just sighted the enemy fleet.
Spotted where?
He reports carriers bearing 320 degrees, 180 miles northwest of Midway.
Well, Leighton, you and Rocheford were only off five minutes, five miles, and five degrees.
Well, we'll endeavor to do better next time, sir.
Give our pilots the enemy position and tell them to attack.
Yes, sir.
They're doing an air-to-air attack.
In other words, they're amateurs.
Even amateurs can do things like that.
The Red Army is trying to attack!
Hey, Lindsey.
You still owe me ten bucks.
Trying to collect before I get myself shot down?
I know you're good for it, Lindsey.
You don't have to fly today.
Nobody without your courage.
I will lead my squadron in.
Good luck, sir.
I'll be right behind you.
I'll meet you at the Japanese fleet.
I see enemy battleships.
I'm sorry, Commander.
This is a report from the scouts.
We've confirmed 10 enemy submarines.
We're heading northeast.
Over.
I'll crush the new threat.
Re-arm the attack aircraft heading for Mido.
While re-arming, we'll give the enemy a chance to escape.
There's a fighter plane.
Range 2,500 yards.
Not wasting a torpedo on a cruiser.
Where are the carriers?
Sir, we need to go deep.
Man battle stations.
The Enterprise has launched its SBDs and their squadrons of Marine dive bombers following a new sighting report out of Midway.
We gotta climb higher, boys.
We need to conserve fuel.
Approaching altitude 14,000 feet.
Release your oxygen, sir.
You okay, sir?
It's my oxygen.
Must have gotten a bad mix.
You have to go back.
You'll tear up your lungs.
I'm not sending the squadron out there without their commander.
There she is.
Got a carrier, maybe 4,000 yards.
Sir, the Japs are right on us.
Make tubes one and two ready.
Make tubes one and two ready in all respects.
Shoes one and two ready, aye.
Blood down, tube one.
Blood down, tube one, aye.
Bering.
Mark.
Matched.
Tube 1.
Six, Baker, Ten, do you have visual?
Nothing.
Must have gotten a bomb sighting report.
Or maybe they changed course.
Let's do a back search.
The screws are fading.
I think they're leaving, sir.
Take us to periscope depth.
Enemy destroyer is headed back to her fleet.
I've got a ship.
Jet destroyer at flag speed.
What do you want to bet she's trying to catch up with the carriers?
Sir, we've been up here for almost two hours.
What if we run out of fuel and the whole squadron has to ditch?
And I'll probably end up scrubbing potatoes at Leavenworth.
Out of hell with it.
Follow me, boys.
I hope you're right, McCluskey.
Bombing six on me.
Have you seen this?
You can't do that with an attack like this.
Stop giving the fighter jets a chance.
They're too slow.
The last attack depends on your mood.
You need a second attack.
Give it to Nagumo.
Yes, sir.
It's a message from Commander Yamaguchi.
He wants us to send the attack team immediately.
What the hell do you think I'm doing?
Genda, report the situation.
Yes, sir.
Are you ready?
We'll do our best, but we'll need time to move from the bomb shelter to Lysol.
We'll need time.
In five minutes.
This place looks like a drug store.
God damn it.
That magnificent son of a bitch actually found them.
All right, boys.
Bombing six.
We got the first bastard in line.
We'll be back soon.
Yes, sir.
All units, charge forward and destroy the enemy's troops.
He was supposed to go for the far carrier.
Stay on me.
Come on, take it easy.
Do what you're paid to do.
Whoo!
There's only us and Akagi left.
We'll talk about it when they attack.
We got a little lonely, sir.
Wish we brought more planes to the party.
You always wanted to be a hero, Kroger.
Now's your chance.
Okay, Mari.
We put that carrier out of action, even if we have to crash on her deck.
Four thousand!
Hurry, sir!
Right on their deck!
Any fighters on our tail?
No, sir!
Flaherty and Guido are down, sir!
If you don't hit them damn Zeros, we're gonna be joining them!
Recharge the carbon dioxide!
The emergency power plant has been destroyed, and there's no power left!
Do you want us to contact Admiral Spruance?
No, he can't break radio silence.
Rochefort intercepted a Japanese signal.
He can't translate the body, but look at the call sign.
That's from Admiral Nagumo, but he's not transmitting from the Akagi.
He's transmitting from a cruiser.
Now, why the hell would Nagumo leave his flagship?
It's a telegram from the mobile force.
Kaga, Soryu, Akagi are under heavy fire.
Our attack seems to have been called by the U.S.
Army.
We've fallen into the trap of the enemy.
You taught us about dehydration in flight school.
Skin starts to crack.
Liver fails.
Knock it off.
What if nobody finds us?
We'll swim back to Toro.
Good luck with sharks.
Then we'll need something to eat.
Wait, wait, I see something.
Looks like a destroyer.
American or Jap?
You!
Tell us your ship, or we throw you overboard.
Cigarette?
You know I had a lot of friends at Pearl Harbor.
So how about you go fuck yourself?
The enemy has three aircraft carriers.
You are the last unharmed aircraft carrier of the fleet.
The fate of Japan is in your hands.
His Majesty is also looking forward to your success.
Don't worry.
Get something to eat.
I bet we're going back out there.
We have to go upstairs to report.
Hey, what happened?
I got strafed by a Zero.
Hey, how'd you know to follow that Jap destroyer?
I played a hunch.
Your hunch might have won us this battle.
I gotta tell you, that looked like some cowboy bullshit to me.
Well, if you can't beat him, join him.
Yorktown's hit.
What have we got left?
A couple of SBDs just returned.
The pilots are coming up to report.
What's the news from the enemy fleet?
Three carriers down, one to go.
And our air group?
Only three torpedo bombers came back, and they're all shot up.
What about the dive bombers?
We can probably scrounge up a dozen.
Klosky, you've been shot.
I can fly, sir.
The hell you can.
Get your ass down to sickbay.
Put the pilots you trust... ...in any plane that can fly.
Yes, sir.
You okay, sir?
I'm fine.
Has anybody heard from Dickinson?
No, not yet.
Look, I know you boys have just been through hell, but we gotta go back and hit the last carrier.
See if I can find more men.
Hey!
Strap up.
We're going back out.
I'm sorry, sir, but I think you need to find somebody else.
You don't know what it's like to be in the back seat, sir.
You fly like you don't care if we come home.
I want to go home, too.
I want to spend more than a few days at a time with my wife.
See my little girl grow up.
And you're right.
If we go up there, we probably aren't coming back.
This is our job.
And we're the guys who have to hold the fort till the cavalry arrives.
Look, if you really can't fly, I'll find someone else.
But you should get back in that plane.
You'll remember this moment for the rest of your life.
And if you know that you came through when people are counting on you, you'll be able to face anything.
We've come this far, Murray.
Don't make me go back out there without you.
I'll warm her up, sir.
The enemy has lost an aircraft carrier and the air force is retreating.
From now on, call the enemy into our fleet and destroy them.
That's a bold strategy.
Contact Hiryu.
Yes, sir.
This is a telegram from the Commander-in-Chief of the Alliance.
It's an order from Chief Yamamoto.
He wants you to keep your eyes on him like a warrior.
Let's go.
Get ready, Murray.
We're not sneaking up on him this time.
Oh.
We got tears on our tail!
This is for Pearl.
Thanks, boys.
What happened to you?
I ran out of fuel about 20 miles out.
Ditched next to the Phelps.
Where's Best?
That's one of his wingmen.
He hasn't come back yet.
He's probably just taking a victory lap.
Yeah.
Hey.
And like Dick Best are the reason we're gonna win this war.
Come on, best.
Thank you.
Any news?
The kids are out back.
Go, go.
Cindy heard a rumor from the base.
There's a big battle.
One of our carriers is sinking.
And the pilots?
Sounds like we lost a lot of them.
I'm gonna go powder my nose quickly.
The Japanese might charge with their battleships.
So we will withdraw for the night.
But their fleet might be out of range in the morning.
Nimitz ordered us to be judicious.
We won a great victory today.
Let's not blow it.
Hang in there, kid.
We're almost home.
I thought you were dead.
Yeah, they said the same thing about you.
I'm glad they were wrong.
Admiral's orders.
Give in to Murray.
He earned it.
Give me a hand.
You okay?
Corpsman!
I need a corpsman!
You fought in the middle.
But the main ship couldn't sink before the enemy could.
It's not you who are responsible for the defeat.
It's us.
That's why I'm determined to join the main ship in fate.
You will continue to be loyal to His Majesty.
That's my final order.
I'll join you, Chief.
Good.
Let's watch the moon together.
All hands!
I'll join you, Chief.
That's my last order.
What happened to Bruno?
PBY flew over his last known position.
They spotted an empty life raft.
Come on!
Here you go.
We couldn't find any reconnaissance aircraft.
We think the enemy's aircraft was launched tonight.
We should shoot down Midway Station.
The U.S.
Navy won't allow us to fight.
We can still win this battle.
You've gone too far.
For the sake of our men, we can't afford to lose the rest of our fleet.
Commander, what is your next order?
The Japanese are retreating.
We won.
Congratulations.
God bless those boys.
Turns out all they needed was a fair fight.
Thank you.
Your son hid this from me.
Half are men.
Dead or missing.
You know?
You know what ever happened to that whiskey?
He's waiting for you to sneak out of sickbay.
Hang on, boys.
Thanks.
Of course.
Hey Layton... ...have a good job.
You boys really came through for us.
Let me get it.
Hey.
Hey, sweetie.
Thank God.
What happened?
Apparently, I inhaled caustic soda.
What does that mean?
My lungs are shot.
The Navy's never gonna let me fly again.
Well, get good at something else.
You have the rest of your life to figure it out.
Thank you.
you
Or nothing at all Half a love never appeared to me If your heart never could yield to me Then I'd rather have nothing at all
or nothing at all if it's love there is no in between why begin then cry for something that might have been no I'd rather have nothing
Oh, please don't bring your lips so close to my cheek Don't smile or I'll be lost beyond recall The kiss in your eyes, the touch of your hand makes me weep
May grow dizzy and fall
And if I fell under the spell of your call, I would be caught in the undertow.
And so you see, I've got to say no.
And so you see, I've got to say no, no.
Thank you.
you