Come on.
When did it start?
At 0500.
We're seven minutes in.
Okay, Private Miller, you've been smoking item nine for seven minutes and 13 seconds.
We're going to ask you several questions.
How do you feel?
Well, sir, I feel like a slice of butter melting on top of a...
Big old pile of flapjacks.
Yeah.
Okay, Private Miller.
When you think of your superiors, what emotions do you feel?
Is this normal?
Okay, Private Miller.
Private Miller.
Answer the question.
This one out, sir.
Can you torch me?
We'll send someone in.
Holy bejesus.
Private Miller, answer the question.
What was the question again, sir?
When you think of your superiors, what emotions do you feel?
You know what problem I have with your fucking little dog and pony act you call the military?
Here it is.
One, lots of dudes.
Where are the boobies?
Two.
Why are we underground right now, sir?
Why can't we be out in the open?
Why aren't we in a square right now?
Why aren't we talking to people, letting them know item nine exists?
Get it out, shout at the rooftops.
This is great.
This is the bee's knees item nine.
Private, we need you to be serious.
I'm serious.
Your dick, my mouth.
That's inappropriate.
Fuck you.
I've seen enough.
Shut it down.
Bury the hatch.
Sell the land.
And dispose of him.
This never happened.
Dude, what happened to your eye?
Hey, hello.
Bleak, bleak, bleak, bleak, bleak, bleak.
Can you guys understand me?
Hey.
Hey, where we going?
This is General Brett.
We've reached a final conclusion on item nine.
illegal!
Hey, this is Sam.
Good morning.
Welcome to KRAD.
You know, I think that last caller had some undeniable points, but right now we're going to get to the next caller, Dale Denton.
Hey, Sam.
Big, huge fan.
First time caller.
Here's my piece.
If marijuana is not legal within the next five years, I have no faith left in humanity, period.
Everyone likes smoking weed.
They have for thousands of years.
They're not going to stop anytime soon, you know?
It makes everything better.
It makes food taste better.
It makes music better.
It makes sex feel better, for God's sakes.
It makes shitty movies better, you know?
Hi there.
Are you Sandra Dambi?
Yeah.
Well, I am Garth from Global Saviors and uh... What is this?
I'm just joking.
You failed to show up for your divorce proceedings like four times under court order and you've been served.
Oh, great.
All right, thanks a lot, asshole.
Sorry.
I'm just saying love has no age.
You can't instantly tell me that a man, because he's a certain age, can't marry a woman or love a woman.
I'm dating a high school girl.
You're not maximizing your potential, baby.
You honestly think this girl takes you seriously?
I like it.
No, but if I'm 25 and the girl is 18 years old, you know, in society, that might look bad, but... Hey, as long as it's consensual.
I think it's consensual.
Yo, you've been subbed.
You've been subbed.
You've been served.
Walter Watzke III.
You here to fix the fax machine?
No, I'm here to tell you who owe Mastercard $4,068.
You've been served by the best, my friend.
Keep it real.
Don't you get a real job, you fucking cocksucker?
Hey, Electric Avenue!
I know, right?
Hey, take that shit to the next level, eh?
Okay, I will.
Dr. Edgar Terrence,
Yes.
You have repeatedly refused to trim the monkey tree that spills onto your neighbor's property, and now because of that, you've been served.
Oh, you're a jerk.
All this current system is doing is putting money in the hands of criminals, and it's making ordinary people like you and me deal with those criminals.
Have you ever dealt with a drug dealer?
It's terrible, it's weird, it's awkward.
They kind of think they're your friend, but they're not your friend.
All right, Dale, get your point.
Thanks for your input.
Next caller, please.
What is it on my rock?
Well, well...
I can't come.
What?
Why the fuck not, Dale?
I just, look, I can't come, okay?
I can't, I just, I have a lot of stuff to do tomorrow.
It's just a bad day for me, okay?
Jesus Christ, Dale, when were you going to tell me that?
I'm sorry, I'm telling you right now.
My mom has been shopping all day long.
Well, why has she been shopping all day?
She's already cleaning her couscous.
I only, I said I might be able to go, so why is she doing that already?
Now I look like an asshole.
You are one.
Oh, come on, don't say that.
I just can't go.
I have a job, okay?
Fine.
Fine?
Don't come.
I don't care.
If you don't care, then why have you been inviting me this whole time?
I thought you wanted me to go.
Because if you don't want to meet them, I don't want you to meet them.
I want to meet them.
I just can't.
I have a job.
I'm sorry.
What do you want from me?
I just know they'll like you, that's all.
You're great.
And you're funny.
And you're sexy.
I just want them to see that.
You want them to see that I'm sexy?
Hey, people.
Hi, Mr. Edwards.
Can I help you?
Uh, no, I'm good.
Thank you, though.
Yeah?
I see you don't have a visitor's badge.
That's why I ask.
I'm, uh, with her, actually.
My boyfriend.
Uh-huh, I heard that.
I wish I didn't hear that, but I just heard that.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'm just wondering why you don't date a nice guy your own age.
She's very mature for her age.
Yeah.
Hey, how's it going?
Hey, Clark, how you doing, man?
What's up?
I'm good, bro.
I'm good.
Dude, I wanted to tell you, you were hilarious today in drama class.
Seriously, your Jeff Goldblum impression made me pee my pants.
I wish.
Oh, hey, I almost forgot.
Last week when we worked out, you forgot your shorts in my car.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, here you go.
Thanks.
Yeah, no problem, no problem, no problem.
Can you hold this?
Yeah.
How's it going, Sporty Spice?
Oh, this is my boyfriend, Dale.
Hey, nice to meet you, man.
You too.
Dude, I've heard so much about you.
You're real cool.
I've heard nothing about you.
I mean, you're great.
Yeah, awesome.
Yeah.
Anyways, uh, yeah, dude, next year.
Next year, college, man.
College.
Yeah, dude, it's gonna be kick-ass.
I will watch your back for you, because I know there's, like, tons of guys that are gonna be trying to get on that shit, so...
Oh, good.
Because I'll got that.
Yeah.
Oh, you got her ass.
No, no.
I mean, I'll watch her ass for... Good.
I'll catch you at home ec.
All right.
Oh, you guys got home ec together, too.
That's cool.
Yeah, yeah.
We got a few classes together.
Good.
Nice to meet you, man.
Time to suck today's dick.
That's what I'm talking about.
That's right.
Hey, I'll see you guys later, all right?
All right, Clark.
Clark's a great guy, man.
He's totally going to take care of Angela, man.
He's great.
He's a wonderful lab partner, so it's going to be cool.
He'll keep an eye on her.
Why don't you go fuck yourself, you weird little prick?
I'm a teacher, okay?
You can't talk to me like that, guy.
I'm not a student, so I can say whatever the fuck I want, you chimp fucking little bastard.
Oh, well, okay, you've got T-minus 30 seconds to get off school property, or I call the police liaison officer.
We're leaving.
29.
Middle finger don't stop the clock.
26.
What's that guy's problem?
Jesus.
I don't know.
He's really weird.
You know what?
I'd love to have dinner with you and your parents tomorrow night.
I'm going to go.
I'll definitely go.
I'll shuffle some things around.
Really?
Yeah, I'll be there for sure.
Yeah, I just want to show them you're in good hands.
Yeah, I mean, I got nothing to be embarrassed about.
Thank you.
That means so much to me and my parents.
Oh, no problem.
It's going to be awesome.
Hello?
Hey, Saul.
Mind if I come by?
Come on down.
Sweet.
Be there.
Hi, Mary.
Hi.
I thought the hurricane season was over.
I thought hurricane season was over.
Oh, I'm sorry about things just got out of hand.
Yeah, that's where it was with my first husband.
Hello?
Hey, man.
What the fuck, man?
I didn't buzz you in.
How the monkey did you get in here?
Oh, shit.
Some guy with a fauxhawk let me in, man.
He was leaving when I was... Kyle, man.
It might have been Kyle.
Absolutely.
I'm sorry, man.
What the fuck's the buzzer for anyway?
I don't know.
I'm sorry about that.
I don't know your protocol yet.
Stuff your sorries in a sack, bro.
It's not your fault.
Okay.
It's these jergoffs.
Have a seat.
Okay, cool.
Thanks, man.
Awesome.
Yo, check this out.
Ah, satellite radio.
Whoa.
Got two TVs and radio.
That's pretty rad.
Nice home entertainment.
Very entertained.
Oh, wow, you got a cute picture, too.
Oh, yeah.
Me and my bubby.
Hey, let me ask you something.
Yeah?
Do you think you could pull the plug on someone if you needed to?
Like euthanasia?
Like on her?
If I needed to.
I'm kind of in a hurry, man.
I don't know if we should start going down that road.
I could talk all day about euthanasia.
Don't get me started.
Maybe we should just... Save it.
We'll save it for next time.
I'll take that rain check, buddy.
We'll keep it going.
Business for the businessman.
Yeah, you got my number.
Okay.
Cool.
Brass tacks.
Yes, yes.
Just got a shipment.
of the dopest dope I've ever smoked.
Hands down, dopest dope I've ever smoked right here.
It's not better than the blue oyster weed.
It can't be.
I can't handle better than that.
This is like if that blue oyster shit met that Afghan kush I had and they had a baby, and then meanwhile, that crazy Northern Lights stuff I had and the super red Espresso snowflake met and had a baby, and by some miracle, those two babies met and fucked, this would be the shit.
That they birthed.
Wow.
Yes.
This is the product of baby fucking.
Smell it.
Okay.
Enjoy.
It's like God's vagina.
Oh.
What, do you want to bathe in it?
I just want to live in here.
Yes, you want to be it?
Oh my God, I just want to shove it up my nose and have that smell all day.
That's amazing.
Shove it anywhere you like.
It's beautiful.
What's it called?
Pineapple Express.
Yes, it's this thing like El Nino, this airflow that comes from Hawaii and Canada, and it gets the dirt, mixes it in with the weed in a very special way.
It's actually very scientific.
I won't go into it right now, but I am the only guy in the whole city that has it.
Only ten bones more for a quarter.
Okay, I'll take a quarter.
All right, you're on.
Thank you very much.
Let me get my scale.
Get it going.
Grab the scale.
Let's get me out of here.
I thought hurricane season was over.
Crow.
Ah, you little fucker.
What the fuck is this thing?
Ah.
Cross joint?
Yeah.
Never smoked one of those?
You can smoke this?
Oh, yeah, man.
No.
This is the future.
This is like the apex of the vortex of joint engineering.
It's rumored that M.M.
O'Shaughnessy designed the first one, the guy who designed the Golden Gate Bridge.
Of course it was.
My second favorite civil engineer behind Hans Carl Bandel, Madison Square Garden.
What you do...
is you light all three ends at the same time.
Really?
And then the smoke converges, creating a trifecta of joint smoking power.
This is it, man.
This is what your grandchildren are going to be smoking.
Future.
The future.
That's amazing.
Well, got the weed in the bag.
Beautiful.
OK.
Be careful with that thing, man.
Here's the cash.
Grab the stash.
All righty, man.
Thanks.
Have a good one.
Don't hurt yourself.
Adios.
Hey, wait a minute, man.
Let's smoke this fucking thing.
I can't, man.
I gotta... I can't even light this thing on my own.
Yeah, I need your help, man.
I'm in.
Come on!
Why not?
Oh, yeah!
Yeah!
Why not?
What do I do?
Okay, here's what you do.
You equip yourself.
I'm equipping.
Okay.
Equip me, sir.
Nice.
Okay.
You are going to light these two ends while I light this end.
Are you ready?
Ready.
Blast off.
I'm gonna do it.
Go for it.
It's like... Makes you ten times more higher than the CrossFit and the Pineapple Express, man.
You're like... Totally fucking gong-showed, man.
Oh, fuck.
Hang on one second, man.
Hang on.
Oh, you fucker.
Oh, shit.
Who is it?
Hey, man, it's Chris G-Bert, man.
Let me up.
Oh, shit.
What's a G-Bert?
Come on up.
I'm not getting any of that pineapple express.
Chris is getting the snickle fritz.
Hey.
So listen, man.
I gotta ask you.
So...
Listen, man, you've been buying from me for, like, two months, right?
Two months.
I gotta ask, man.
What's up with this suit?
Well, I'm a process server, so I have to wear a suit.
Wow.
You're a servant?
Like, a butler?
A chauffeur?
No, no.
What?
No, I'm not like... Shine shoes?
I'm a process server.
I like... In process.
I work for a company that's like hired by lawyers to like hand out legal documents like subpoenas to people who don't want them.
So I got to wear like disguises sometimes just to make them admit that they're themselves so I can...
Served them the papers.
Disguise.
Kind of, I guess.
It's a hell of a job.
That's cool, man.
Like, a day-to-day basis, it's fine.
Like, today, I, like, sat in my car, I smoked, like, ten doobies, and then, like, went to go visit my girlfriend at lunch.
Nice.
What?
Yeah, it was badass.
Sucked on her titties?
No, I just kissed her.
I just did that to make it seem cool.
That's cool.
Does she like to smoke weed?
Um, a little, sometimes.
She has a couple.
She's in high school, so, you know, as much as any high school kid, she's cool as hell, actually.
You'd probably get along with her, I guess.
Yeah, you know, it only sucks because when I go visit her in high school and all the guys she goes to school with are, like,
strong and like handsome and really like funny, like do good impressions of Jeff Goldblum and shit like that.
And like, I just feel like a fat, dumb, fucking stinky ass turd when I'm there.
It really, it sucks for my ego.
Fuck Jeff Goldblum, man.
That's what I say.
You know, don't get down on yourself.
You got a great girl.
You got a great job where you don't do anything.
You get to smoke weed all day.
I wish I had that.
Are you kidding?
You do.
You have the easiest job on earth.
You do smoke weed all day.
That's true.
You didn't think of that.
I do have a good job.
Yeah, you do nothing.
Thanks, man.
No problem.
Thank you.
Oh, shit.
All right.
Business.
Got my persona.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
All right.
Hey, put that cross joint out, man.
He sees that, he'll never get the fuck out of here.
OK.
What's up, Chris?
Yo, hey, Sal.
Hey.
How you doing, buddy?
All right, Holmes.
Good.
Who's this?
Hey.
Oh, this is my friend, Mark.
All right.
Got the dough?
Here you go.
Appreciate it.
Thanks.
Nice.
Good to meet you, Mark.
Hey, Sal.
Do you have any Percocet, please?
Percocet?
What are you talking about, man?
I don't sell that shit.
Chris.
Who said Percocet?
You told him I was going to sell Percocet?
Don't say anything about Percocet.
What the fuck, man?
What the fuck?
Man, I just wanted a cup of Percocet.
Well, I came to the wrong place, my friend.
Wrong place.
Yeah, nice.
Peace out, Holmes.
Thank you.
God.
The fuck?
Yeah.
Fucking linger, man.
Yeah, totally.
Linger.
Hardcore.
Fuck.
Bums me out.
Bums me out, too.
If there's one quality I hate in a person, it's lingering.
That's right.
You and me both.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, so I'm curious.
What have those people done that you go and process and service?
Um, I don't know.
It's always something different, I guess.
This guy...
Ted Jones, who knows, you know, it could be... Oh, Ted Jones?
Yeah, why?
My guy Red, who I buy from, he gets his stuff from a Ted Jones.
Really?
Maybe it's the same guy.
That'd be weird, it's a pretty normal name, I guess, but... Eh.
Anyway, I should really get going, man.
I gotta go.
Duty calls, but it's good to see you.
What?
Thanks.
You gonna smoke and run?
Come on, man.
We can go look at some crazy things on the internet together.
That sounds appealing, but you know what?
I'll tell you here.
I'm going to run out of weed in a couple of days.
I'll just come by.
We'll hang out.
We'll watch 227 and shit.
Oh, definitely.
Cool, man.
All right, man.
Well, thanks.
Good to see you, man.
All right, peace, brother.
OK, yeah.
One love.
When you got behind on the mortgage, I guess someone finally made you alone.
Yeah, CDN.
What was the interest rate you got?
Airway.
Hello?
Hey, Angie, what's happening?
Hey, I just talked to my mom, and they were so excited that you're coming for dinner.
I mean, like, so excited.
I'm so am I, but we're all really excited.
Thank you so much.
No problem.
I'm psyched, too.
It's going to be awesome.
Koos koos.
The food's so nice, they named it twice.
Um, Dale, anyway, look, I can't wait for next year when this bullshit is over.
I mean, when I have... Oh, shit, I see the guy who got us served.
I'll call you back.
Fucking cops.
Oh, shit.
Jesus.
What an adorable little cop.
Jesus, fuck.
What the fuck was that?
Oh shit.
Dude, dude, dude, dude.
Oh no!
Jeff, Jeff!
Who the fuck is that?
I don't know, but I'm waiting to see.
First drive!
I'm so afraid to fly!
Pineapple Express.
Oh my god!
I saw brains and blood!
I can't know!
Where do I go?
Hello?
Saul, it's Dale, let me in, let me in, let me in!
I just saw some crazy shit, man, let me in, please, for the love of God, let me in!
It's Dale, let me in, man, let me in!
Dale?
Yes, Dale, that's what I said, it's Dale, Dale, let me in!
Oh, alright, man, come on up.
I buzzed it, open the door when I buzz it.
Buzz it in three seconds, exactly.
One, two!
Did it work?
On three!
I did it on three.
On one, two, three, go?
No, man.
He fucking killed him, man!
Hey, I got neighbors.
He fucking killed him!
What?
Who killed who?
A cop!
A lady and a guy!
Man, that's like a massacre.
You saw it?
No, it was just a guy.
What happened to the lady?
No, no, a woman, a police woman, and a guy, another guy shot another guy, an Asian guy, in the window at fucking Ted's house.
Was the other guy Ted?
I don't know.
He was a big gray-haired man, and he had a robe, and he fucking took a gun, and he shot him, and his brain fucking flew everywhere.
I'm going to be, I'm going to throw up.
What?
Oh, chicken fries.
Sick.
You threw up in my printer.
I did.
Did you break it?
I hope not.
Listen, man, I think the guy was Ted, and the Asians are number two in town, so you saw Ted capping the competition.
They saw me.
They saw me see them shoot the guy.
What?
They saw you?
And you fucking came here?
No, no.
Did they follow you here?
I don't know.
Look, look.
Okay, here's what happened.
I saw him kill him.
I freaked out.
I panicked, okay?
I tossed my roach.
I crashed into two cars.
So they would have heard.
They must have heard.
They know someone was out there.
They know someone saw.
They know someone.
They don't know it was you.
Right?
I don't... I mean, I don't know.
Yes.
I hope not.
Relax.
Sit back.
Get ready to enjoy some of the rarest weed known to mankind.
Is it really that rare?
It's like the rarest.
It's almost a shame to smoke it.
It's like killing a unicorn with like a bomb.
Are you the only guy in town who has this?
You're actually the only guy?
Yeah.
My guy Red said he was giving me an exclusive sneak preview.
And am I the only guy who you sold it to?
The other guy's got Snickle Fritz?
Yeah.
So we're like the only guys.
And Red got this from Ted?
Ted's the man.
Let's get the fuck out of here, man!
Go!
Let's go!
Because I threw a roach at this outside of Ted's house!
So what, man?
I throw roaches all over the fucking town!
No!
He could find the roach and say, it's Pineapple Express in here!
Saul is the only guy who has Pineapple Express!
He must have seen the murderer!
No!
Let's fucking kill him!
Let's get out of here!
Wait!
Stop!
Get weed!
Get the weed!
Get anything you might need!
Snacks!
Food!
Fruit roll-ups!
Let's get the fuck out of here!
Okay!
Red said he'd be here.
Yeah!
Mmm, dump some drugs.
Smells like vomit in this house.
Wanna hit, man?
Still lit?
I'm having dinner with my wife.
She can always tell.
Smell it on my sweater.
For real?
Yeah, for real.
Want one of my vests?
They smell good.
Not my style.
You ain't got no style, motherfucker.
You have reached the voicemail box of... Ted?
Ted, it's Bud Lofsky.
We're here.
Saul's gone.
At Matheson.
Yeah, I think he knew we were coming.
They're not here, Ted.
Hi, Ted.
Okay, what do you know about Ted?
Um, I think he's, like, crazy about murdering.
Well, that's not good!
Where the hell are we gonna go?
Let's just go, let's go to a motel or, like, a hotel or a holiday inn and just hide out.
No, no, no, no.
The police were in on it.
They could have flagged our credit cards.
No, no, no, no, no.
They'll find us.
Shit.
I wish we could just go nowhere.
Okay, even if he found that roach, how could he know where you are?
Um, he's seeking missiles, um, bloodhounds, foxes, barracudas.
I'm just, I'm kind of flabbergasted when you say things like that.
It's weird.
Thank you.
Not a compliment.
Here's the question.
Let's say he actually found the roach.
How could he, how could he connect the Pineapple Express weed to you
Yeah, man.
Only fucking Red knows.
Only Red knows, man.
Who is Red?
Red's, like, the middleman between, like, Ted and me.
And we're, like, mad fucking tight, man.
One time, he got this girl, gave me a handjob, like, within five minutes of meeting her.
I was like, like, I don't even know your name.
That is pretty rad.
But, like, let's say Ted calls him and is like,
Hey, did you sell the pineapple express to anyone?
He'll be like, yeah, so-and-so.
Because why wouldn't he, you know?
No.
Oh, no.
Fuck that, man.
Fucking hand job, Dale.
I mean, imagine if I gave you a hand job.
Why would I want to do that?
No, I mean, like, if I got you a hand job.
Yeah, but the same rules don't apply to Red.
He's a drug dealer.
I'm a drug dealer.
What are you saying, you don't trust me?
No, that's not at all what I'm... You know what?
That's, you know, just ignore what I said.
Call him.
Give him a call.
See what the dealio is.
Ow!
Hello?
Hey, Red, you OK?
Yeah, yeah, it's solved.
Yeah, I'm fine, man.
I just stubbed my toe.
Oh, well, be careful, man.
Be careful.
Where's shoes in the house?
Safety.
Safety first, then teamwork.
Now listen.
You know that Pineapple Express stuff you gave me?
Don't tell anybody that you sold it to me.
I would never talk to anyone about the stuff that I do with you involving drugs.
All right, cool.
Now listen, I'm gonna come by.
I gotta lay some shit on you.
There is a fly in the ointment.
Shit, is it the fan?
The lion will speak.
Let me have a convo, please.
No, seriously.
Listen, we're gonna be over there in like half an hour.
No, please.
No, no, no, no, no.
Let's just go over there and chill out, man.
No, man, come on.
Can we go tomorrow?
Look, we're already here.
Do you have somebody else?
Somebody else on the phone with him?
Who's he talking to?
I don't know.
He's whispering to another man.
We'll go in the morning.
It's better that way.
Thank you.
Yes.
Hey.
So you're coming by tomorrow?
How'd you know that?
Yeah, I just heard you whispering to that other guy that you're talking to.
Who is that?
Oh, right, Dale.
Good job.
Listen, I can't go in the morning because my bubby, I got to change the clocks.
Daylight savings.
Yeah, is that the bubby that's on 41st and River Street?
The one where we played that shuffleboard that one time?
You got it.
So listen, we'll be chilling by noon, all right?
Noon it is, bromo-sexual.
Nice.
Hey, we should hit up the casino again, man.
It's been a while.
OK, yeah, we'll definitely hit the casino up.
Definitely.
All right, peace, brother.
I should call Angie soon.
Make up some bullshit.
I'm cold.
You're cold?
Oh, I'm not cold at all.
Here.
I run hot.
Really?
Yeah.
You got more body?
Thick blood.
Yeah, no, take it.
Hmm, space.
Dale, wait, wait.
The phones, the phones.
You said they were cops, right?
They are cops, yeah.
Yeah, so I'm just thinking, like, maybe they can triangulate these things, man, or, like, you know, like, trace them, right?
They totally, that's how they got Saddam.
Right.
Fuck, you're right, man.
Well, maybe they can, like, even trace them, like, when we're not even on them.
You know, maybe... Maybe if we bury him under the dirt, the reception will get cut off and they won't be able to do it.
It'd be great if we could, like, tie it to an animal and, like, be, like, diversion.
Distraction will never catch an animal.
Like, the squirrel would be up in the tree and they'd think we were in the tree.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Uh, we'll build a hot air balloon and... And then just... No.
We'll smash him!
Yeah, yeah.
I'm gonna smash it!
On a rock!
Okay, good idea.
Right here!
Yes!
Good thinking!
Ha!
Yeah, get it!
Die!
Yes!
Whoa!
The fuck was that?
I was trying to hit that tree.
I missed.
What tree?
Why didn't you smash it on a rock like a normal person like I do?
I don't know.
How often does somebody smash things?
I'm rusty.
Man, did you at least see where it landed?
I don't know.
Call it.
Call it with what?
My phone has been smashed.
You know what?
I bet they can't even triangulate those things.
You shouldn't have said anything, because now you convinced me they can.
You were very convincing back there.
Hey, fine.
Go find it.
Fuck.
Do you see it?
See what?
The phone, you idiot.
Why are we here?
This place is so fucking scary.
At least I had an idea.
You didn't even have any ideas.
Shut up.
That's not true.
I had two ideas.
Isn't it?
Nowhere in Quiznos.
Shh.
What?
What was that?
What is that?
What?
Shh.
I hear something.
Shush, shush, shush.
Oh, fuck!
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
What are you running from?
Return to me now!
No, no!
Help me!
Please help me!
Be with me!
I'm scared of this darkness!
I surrender!
Go away, go away!
I'm so lost!
This isn't funny anymore!
Dale!
Fall back!
Save me!
Ow!
Open it!
Open the door!
Unlock it!
I can't unlock it!
What are you doing, man?
Go!
I saw something!
I saw a forest creature!
What did you see?
Just shut up!
Shut the fuck... Shut up, man!
Shush!
What was that?
I heard something, then I saw something.
You didn't hear anything, man.
I saw something.
Are you telling me that guy in the little short shorts broke your nose?
Right.
The bedazzler guy broke your nose?
Tough man?
Wake up.
Whoa.
Why did I get on you?
Oh, watch finally broke.
Crazy.
What time is it?
Well, that can't be right.
Couldn't be 3 in the morning, could it?
It's 3 o'clock right now?
Holy shit, man.
We were supposed to be at Red's at noon, man.
What if he's gone?
What if we don't get any information now?
No, it's daylight savings, so... So it's only 2 o'clock?
Oh, no.
It went forward an hour.
It's four o'clock?
Fuck me.
No, man, that's bad.
Shit.
We slept for like 18 hours.
My bubby, man.
My bubby's gonna be so pissed.
Shit.
We gotta call Red.
Okay.
How?
We'll go to a pay phone.
No, I can't.
His number was in my phone.
Great.
Well, do you remember where he lives?
Yeah, I know where he lives.
What are you insinuating, like I'm forgetful?
Insinuating?
Good one.
Do you know what that means?
I do know what it means, believe it or not.
To seem like.
Let's roll, man.
I'm done with the woods.
Let's go.
Come on, man.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Okay, let's go.
No, it's not working.
The battery's dead.
Wait.
What do you mean it's dead?
What do I mean?
I mean the battery's dead.
The battery's dead.
What do you mean the battery's dead?
How can I explain this to you differently?
The battery is dead.
It ceased to live.
It's deceased now.
The car needs a battery to start, Saul.
How did this happen?
Well, we clearly fell asleep with the battery on and... Oh, man.
Talk radio?
Yes, talk radio.
It's so boring, man.
Okay, okay.
The car just committed suicide.
Just don't... Shut up, man.
I have an idea now.
We're gonna go...
We'll walk back to the road.
We'll hitchhike.
Someone will pick us up.
That guy will take us to Red's.
Red will tell us that everything's fine and everything will go back to normal.
How does that sound?
Does that sound good?
That's a good idea.
Keep our heads on straight, man.
If we just keep thinking like this, we're fucking gravy.
All right.
I'm in.
Let's do it.
Can I have my jacket back, please?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Thanks for taking care of it.
Hey, look, it's like my thumb is my cock.
That's not going to get us a ride, man.
Here's good.
Thanks for the smooth sailing, Cherie.
Who is it?
It's Bruce.
Bruce?
Who the fuck is this?
Saul!
What's up?
Who's this?
I'm Dale, Mr. Red.
Nice to meet you.
Dale who?
You know, it's probably best if you don't know my full name.
Dale Denton.
Don't worry, he's with me.
Nice to meet you, bro.
Hold on, let me get this lock, okay?
You better.
Get in here.
Coming in.
Y'all want to buy some drugs?
Frisk me.
Yeah.
What's up?
Give it.
Oh, look at that, huh?
What's up, players?
What's up?
I've been up in here trying to get a motherfucking scholarship.
Chilling.
What's up with the clothes?
Oh, we were camping.
Camping?
Yeah.
Is your lip okay, man?
You been crying?
Oh, my lip.
It's a cold sore.
Never had one before, so I started to cry.
I think it's just like a lot worse than it looks, though.
It's like a simple kind of... Cold sore?
Does that mean fucking herpes?
Yeah.
Yeah, yes, it does.
Fucking sick, man.
You know how many joints we've shared?
I know.
I'm a disgusting person.
Oh.
Herpes is for life, bro.
Yeah, well, I'm gonna try to definitely put some sort of medical ointment on it.
I've been taking Vicodin.
That doesn't really take the swelling down, though.
It's from that time I told you, man.
You wanted to eat that lollipop out of that stripper's snatch.
You wanted to do it.
Out of her vagina, I know.
Remember what you did?
What'd you do?
Nothing.
You ate a box of Nerds out of her...
Butthole.
Fucking said you wouldn't tell.
You sowed your own poison, man.
Dude, seriously, we're here for a reason.
Just ask him.
Chill, dude.
Chill.
I'm boiling some eggs over here.
That's great.
We got a lot of time to hang out.
I'm making a fucking cake.
No shit.
Just ask him, man.
What are you doing?
Don't ask for a piece.
I can't have a piece of that?
No, you can't have a piece.
This is private.
Do you know what today is?
Tuesday.
This is my cat's birthday today.
I don't see a cat in here.
I'm sorry.
We let it out by accident?
No, because he died three months ago, okay?
So now who's the funny guy?
Sorry.
All right?
Today is his birthday, and it is a tradition that on his birthday, I'd get up extra early and make him his favorite kind of dessert.
Don't worry, bro.
Your cat's going to heaven.
Yeah, maybe.
Maybe he went to heaven.
He was a little fucker.
He could have gone to hell.
Why don't we talk, guys?
Ask him.
Just ask him, okay?
Seriously.
Ask what?
Just come straight.
What's up?
Yeah, right.
Lay it on him.
What's going on?
Right on.
We need to know about your source.
Ted.
Ted Jones.
See, Dale here is a protest servant.
No, I'm not.
That's not what I am.
He's not that, but he was outside Ted's house.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Don't.
Look, uh, we don't want to bring you in to what we're in, okay?
You don't want any trouble.
We don't want to give you trouble.
So it's probably best you don't know the whole story, okay?
You don't think I can handle danger?
What are you talking about?
You can.
I totally can.
And for you to come into my house and not tell secrets because you think you're saving me, well, in reality, it just makes you look like a dumbass, okay?
Because look at this.
See this?
You see that?
There's no hair under here, bro.
Okay?
What's the significance of that?
It makes me aerodynamic when I fight.
I can take danger.
Okay.
Has anyone called asking about salt or the pineapple express or anything?
That's all we need to know.
Uh-uh.
Uh-uh?
Is it uh-huh or uh-uh?
It's uh-uh.
There it is, man.
Cleared.
Over.
Everything's fine, I told you, bro.
We had a wacky night in the woods, but we both can put that behind us like adults.
Now it's time to get super-duper high.
You got that bong I got you in Tel Aviv?
Bong mitzvah.
Hit it up, dude.
Yes.
There you go.
Why don't you follow his lead and just chill out, man?
I'm chill.
I'm chill as a cucumber, man.
You don't seem chill.
I'm more chill than you.
You're more chill than me?
Yeah.
Look what I'm wearing.
Come on now, dawg.
What are you wearing?
A suit.
Yeah, exactly.
I don't know what's up with you, but I don't know if I like you.
Well, I don't know if I like you either, man.
Well, that's your loss, because I'm a great friend.
I'm going to use the telephone to call my wife, OK?
Give her a call.
I will.
Go ahead.
Don't pay attention to what I'm saying.
Oh, I won't.
Bullshit!
Nothing.
Liar.
What are you doing, man?
He's a liar.
He's lying to us, man.
He's lying to us.
No, he's not.
He knows my name.
He's acting weird.
Talk to your boy.
We can't let him phone anyone, man.
No, you're freaking out, man.
You're paranoid.
Talk to your boy.
I do not trust you, sir.
You're paranoid.
He's acting weird.
I'm not.
Fred, I'm sorry, bro.
Oh, Jesus.
Holy cock.
Fuck you.
What are you doing, man?
He's sorry.
Oh, Jesus.
I don't want to have to do this.
Ray, you're crazy, man.
I brought the devil into my house.
We're friends.
I know we are.
That guy sucks.
You want that mad shit again?
Toilet.
Flush.
What we do in this life echoes in eternity.
Oh, no.
He's going for the phone!
To call Ted!
Stay out of here!
Red!
Don't do it!
You assholes, you ruined my portable phone!
Teamwork.
Yes!
You gotta break the door!
Are you gonna pay for it?
What'd you tell Ted?
You're special about balls!
Smash him!
Oh, fuck!
Ow!
Time out!
Okay, truce.
Come in!
Thank you!
Cheater!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
Red!
Shit!
Oh, fuck!
Oh, God!
Hey, take it, mate!
Time out!
No!
No, no, no, no, no!
Where are you going, huh?
Where do you think you're going, Mr. Wiggles?
Come on!
Get back here!
Saul, help me!
Help me!
He's punching my bum!
I'm done with this!
Let's talk!
Let's try words!
Use words!
No!
You okay, man?
Look, I'll get you another bong, all right?
It's my cat's birthday today.
Happy birthday.
All right?
Give me some...
Hey, there's a package in the mailbox.
This ends now!
Oh, shit.
Was that too much?
Can't get the edge.
Wait, got it, got it.
Hey, Dale, do you think we're gonna have to kill him?
Because I don't think I'm capable of murder.
I don't think I am either.
Maybe we could just convince him to kill himself.
Or just not say anything.
We need to find out everything he knows, okay?
Wake up.
Hey, what's up dudes?
What's up?
Tell us everything now.
Talk red.
I'm gonna flex and bust out of here.
Trapped.
It's not happening, Red.
Okay.
All right.
Okay, I'll talk.
Ted Jones, he knows you witnessed the murder.
He found your roach.
He sent two guys over here, Budlovsky and Matheson, two real big son-of-a-bitches, and they're basically out to kill you guys.
Yeah, and they're going to kill me, too, unless I turn you all over.
So you guys are basically fucked.
Fuck it.
They're my friends.
How many cops does he have on his payroll?
Tell us.
Well, there's the woman cop, Carol, and I don't know, he could have a bunch.
I mean, this dude is like super well connected and he has like a really awesome hideout too.
It's pretty badass.
Oh, shit.
What else?
Okay, he's at a war right now with the Asians.
They're like in a drug war right now.
What Asians?
Indians are technically Asian.
It's true.
What Asians?
I don't know.
Chinese or Korean or... Viet Cong?
Yeah.
Little, little, just little Asian people like the Asians with the guns and the drugs and not his friends.
Oh, shit!
Okay, guys, I know I sold you all out.
Now, I've been a real son of a bitch and a shitty friend.
Saul, I'm talking to you.
Dale, you're a new friend.
But I can make it up, okay?
I forgot bros before hoes.
Just go out the back porch.
I won't say anything, okay?
I'll cover for you.
Okay, thanks, man.
No sweat.
It was Dale Denton!
Dale Denton and Saul!
They were on the back porch!
You can catch them if you hurry!
Go, go, go!
Hey, in here.
Whoa, whoa.
I've got to get to a phone van.
Come on.
We should hide.
Why?
No, look.
OK, if Red tells Ted's guys about my name, then they'll go to my apartment.
And there, I have Angie's name.
And they can put that all together, and they'll find her.
Let's go.
No, no, no.
I think we should stay.
Why?
Because I'm in the dumpster already.
Well, then get out.
Come on.
You're already dirty.
They're gone.
Well, find out what he knows.
Red, it's your last chance, man.
You gonna give him something we can use?
Matheson, man, you gotta be kidding me, man.
I mean, what more do you want?
I told you that the guy's name is Dale Denton, he's obviously working with Saul, that they came in here, they busted my house to shit, they kicked the hell out of me, and then duct taped me to my grandfather's wheelchair.
I mean, what more do you want me to tell you?
Want me to read your horoscope?
You hear that, Ted?
Okay, ask if either of them were Asian.
What's a gay-colored wedding?
They were white people.
Denton might have been a Jew.
I don't know.
I don't judge people based on things like that.
Obviously, we're friends.
Mm-hmm.
Ted, you hear him?
Dale Denton, not Asian.
All right, kill Red.
Man, listen, I would just appreciate it if both of y'all would just take your shoes off me.
And this is brand new carpet, you're tracking mud in here.
Madison, you got British Knights on.
I ain't seen anybody wear them since 1987.
No!
What the hell are you doing?
Ted told me to kill him.
Well, how about a little fucking discretion here?
See?
See right there.
You see that?
You catch it?
See what?
You used to not give a fuck about discretion.
I think you pulled somebody's jawbone off.
I think that you was ruthless.
You was ruthless, man.
What the fuck, man?
You shot me in my stomach.
I'm gonna die now, probably.
Man, I had you all over here for dinner.
Fish tacos.
This how you do me?
So what did Budlovsky and Matheson say?
I don't know.
There's this guy, Saul.
something, who's selling weed, who works with some guy named Dale Denton.
That's all he said.
That's all I got out of it.
Do you think he has anything to do with the guy that we shot?
Well, did he say anything else?
Saul mentioned something about going to the casino.
Weird.
Going to the casino?
The Asians own the casino, Ted.
I need another beer.
He's got to be working for them.
Maybe after we pop that guy, they hired this outside guy, Dale, what's his name, Denton, to finish the job.
Maybe.
Well, I'll be back in an hour.
I'll have everything there is to know about this, uh, Dale Denton guy.
Who he's screwing, who's his mother, everything.
Wait, where are we going?
I gotta, I gotta, I gotta get Tangie's.
I have to make sure she's okay.
What about my bubby?
You don't think they'll go after her, do you?
I mean, she has a, she has a different last name.
Pelogis.
I don't know.
We should get out of the middle of the road, though.
Come on.
You guys can wait as long as you want, but one minute from right now, I'm gonna eat some food.
And you can call it rude, you can call whatever you want, and you can be all polite with your clean plates, but I'm gonna be eating food.
And I'm gonna go in the other room and eat it and check my email, because I'm done with this.
Honey, we're at the table.
No one's going to leave the table.
Okay, this is it.
I'm going alone.
What?
No.
Yeah, yeah.
I want to meet Angie.
You'll meet her later, man.
Look, I need you to stay out here.
Keep guard, okay?
It's really important.
Watch my back.
Okay.
Thanks.
All right.
Just be yourself.
I'll keep guard.
Hey.
Oh, shit.
Oh, no.
Hey, Dale.
Hello, Dale.
Hey.
Dinner.
This is the dinner you invited me to.
That was tonight.
That's why I'm here.
Sit.
Please.
Of course.
Hi.
Shannon.
Intros, Shannon.
Great to meet you.
You too, Robert, if I'm not mistaken.
Sit on down so we can eat.
I'll sit.
Oh my God.
Hey.
Okay.
What the hell happened to you?
Nothing.
I'm supposed to be here right now.
So I'm here.
You're all dirty and bleeding.
No, I'm not.
I'm here for dinner.
You have scratches on your forehead.
Dude, you smell like shit.
Dale, what happened to you?
I was in the woods.
In the woods?
Yeah, isn't that weird?
I was in the woods.
What were you doing in the woods?
I birdwatched.
I don't.
No, I don't.
Look, I'm going to come clean.
I witnessed a murder, okay?
I saw someone murder someone else, and I think they've been following me.
And there's a good chance they went to my apartment where Angie has a lot of things.
She has her yearbooks, report cards, her cell number is written, and it's on my fridge.
So they could then find this house.
They could come here.
We should call the police right away.
We can't call the police.
The police were the murderers.
That's what's so flipping scary.
They were the murderers.
Angie, I swear to God, you'll do something where I'm going to.
So fucked up.
No, don't.
Don't let him gonna.
No, don't wanna.
Look, we gotta get the F out of here.
Let's go.
We need to begin to prematurely evacuate.
Are you high?
What?
No, I'm not high.
You are high as a fucking kite.
I'm not high.
Let's go.
We're not going anywhere.
I'm coming back in a minute.
You know what I'm coming back with?
No, what?
I'm coming back with a gun.
You better be out of here.
Robert, don't.
I'm not fucking with you.
Your gun?
His gun?
Why do you ever don't get a gun?
Why would he bear arms?
Look, no.
We need to go.
Everyone, I'm leading the parade.
This is so exciting
Okay, okay, is this where you're parked?
Let's sally forth!
Who is after you, after Angie?
They're drug dealers.
I have reason to believe that they're drug dealers.
Seriously, what are you talking about?
This is crazy, you're out of your mind.
I know, it sounds crazy.
Hi.
No, no, no, it's happening!
Why'd you do that?
Get it!
Okay, just stop.
Angie, what did you do?
He's one of the drug dealers!
Get out!
He's my pot dealer!
He's your pot dealer?
Get it!
Ow!
Are you OK?
Dale, who is this?
He's my dad!
Oh, shit, get down!
What was that?
That was a gunshot.
He's with me!
He is with me!
Now put the gun down!
Put down the gun!
You assholes do exactly what I say or I will take you outside and fuck you in the street!
No!
Don't do that!
Don't fuck us anywhere!
Anybody out there?
I'm gonna be hiding shit.
Let's see now.
Hey, the food's still warm.
Come on, Saul.
Come on.
Yes.
We made it.
We're all safe, guys.
What are you doing?
Get the fuck out of my car.
I can't even believe you think that would be an option.
Okay.
No, that makes sense.
It makes sense.
Come on.
Let's go.
It makes sense.
He's right.
Stay away from my family.
Period.
So where do we go?
What do we do?
Go to the Days Inn downtown, okay?
Use a fake name.
Garagely, I'll contact you.
Look, I don't know who these people are.
I don't know what they're capable of, but I will keep you guys safe.
I promise that.
I'll keep you safe.
Fuck off, loser.
Angie, you're a fucking idiot.
I say that with love.
So get this.
We triangulated the cells, and they smashed one, and then they threw the other one in the woods to try to distract us.
An hour for Jared to find it.
And then he said that he found Denton's car filled with all these strange disguises.
A powdered wig, a sombrero, leotards.
I mean, what the fuck does that mean, you know?
But why don't I just call the Asians and talk to Chung?
Why be around the bush?
Hello?
Chung, it's Ted.
Ted, what a surprise.
What can I do for you?
Well, Chung, my friend, let me tell you.
You know, we both know that you sent one of your very skilled hitmen over here last night.
And I and my colleague made a little decoration on our window.
Should have seen it.
We painted the wall with his brain and painted it.
And now this Dale Denton guy?
You serious?
Just stop it, okay?
Stop it, or you're asking for war.
Do you want a war?
Fuck your mama.
All right, you listen to me, chum.
You motherfucker!
It is on!
We're coming at you with everything we got!
It's on, so you better get your head out of your ass and be ready for everything!
You are fucking dead!
You're so dumb.
Do you have any idea how weak you just made us look?
God damn it!
Kisaki, Ted Jones, Torai, we shall strike now with full force.
Your brother's death will not be in vain.
I gotta say, I've had, like, a lot of weed dealers in my day.
You're by far the coolest I've ever had, man.
They were all dicks.
Really?
Yeah.
Thanks, man.
No problem.
I really appreciate it.
That means a lot to me, you know?
It's like you're the first guy that I ever sold to that I became friends with.
They say, like, don't dip the pen in company ink.
I'm totally glad I dipped in your ink, bro.
Yeah.
So we should get out of town, probably.
That's probably our next move.
We just get on the bus and leave, right?
Get bus tickets, go to the next town, contact some police.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, I'm totally, like... You're glad you dipped your pen, like, yeah, but we should go, we should get bus tickets and leave, right?
What?
Get on the bus, leave, buy bus tickets.
Yeah, I only have, like, 50 bucks.
I don't think I'll even buy one ticket.
What about your sack?
Oh, man, it's fucking killing me.
I feel like I'd pop one.
Ew, no, that's unfortunate, but that's not what I'm talking about.
I mean, like, the sack of weed.
Wouldn't we just, like, sell some weed and get some cash and buy bus tickets?
Of course, man, that's what I'd do.
That's what you do.
Fucking A. Okay, so you're gonna buy tickets for Saturday's game, right?
These guys are amazing.
Psst.
What the fuck do you want?
You guys want to buy some Chronic?
What's this stuff called again, man?
Pineapple Express.
They said it like eight times, you fucking tod.
Yeah, but don't call it that.
Don't call it that.
Yeah, if anyone asks, that's not what it's called.
Call it banana bogey, all right?
Just make sure you're leaving the weed, too.
You know, this could be a gateway drug.
You don't want to move on to other things.
Cocaine, don't do that.
We don't fuck around.
Don't worry.
Don't tell us what to do.
Inhale it, Chachi.
Inhale it.
Who the fuck's Chachi?
How much money you guys got?
Come on, Zap.
You each get as much as you can grab with one hand.
Let's go easy.
That's a big handful, guys.
Come on.
OK, just keep it on the down low.
Don't tell anybody where you got it, all right?
You got it from, I mean, you got it from Santiago and Dunbar.
Let's go.
Go, go, bamboos.
You fucking did it, man.
Good.
You are a good salesman.
You got it in you, man.
I'm about to go get some celebratory snacks.
Yeah, get some snacks.
What do you want?
Get some burritos or something.
I don't know.
Something to drink, too.
Something good.
See you, man.
Nice.
Don't move.
Don't you move.
This shit hurts.
Don't move.
What's in your hand?
It's weed.
It's a joint.
It's a roach.
I'm sorry.
Come here.
Right here.
Uh, I was just smoking this.
What's in your hand?
I thought it was decriminalized, to be honest with you.
I have a horrible anorexia, and it helps my appetite.
I'm so sorry.
Look, selling?
Narcotics to my students.
It's not decriminalized.
Okay, I understand that.
I'm the liaison officer for this school.
And guess what?
I just saw three students walking from back here with their eyes as red as the devil's dick.
You're busted.
Those kids came up and they peer-pressured me.
This is terrible.
There's nobody in your room.
On the hood.
OK, I'm on the hood.
Whoa, come on.
Stand still.
OK, I'm still.
I'm still.
OK, on the hood.
I'm sorry.
OK, I'm on the hood.
You better hope it's clean.
You better hope ain't shit on this record.
I'm clean.
I'm going to put my foot up in your way.
Oh, big sexy with glasses.
This is Officer Barber requesting an update on fugitive Dale Denton.
I repeat, requesting update on Dale Denton.
I have the fugitive in custody.
425, 425, what's your location?
You going down.
What?
What do you mean I'm going?
Why am I going down?
What did that thing tell you?
What did I tell you?
What are you doing?
What do you think?
Why do you hate me so much?
What did that thing say?
Hit and run, Mr. Denton.
Hit and run.
Shit.
Two parked cars two nights ago, and one of them was actually a police cruiser.
Oh, no.
You've got to be the dumbest motherfucker in California.
Oh, my God.
So you telling me you saw Ted Jones and a police officer shoot somebody?
That's exactly what I'm telling you.
Do you believe me?
And you saw it?
Yes, do you believe me?
I don't know.
Give me a minute.
It was a woman or a man?
It was a policewoman.
It was a woman.
Oh, I think I know who that bitch was.
Yes, I will identify that bitch.
Thank you so much for believing me, ma'am.
Thank you so much.
Well, I tell you this.
I bet I get to the bottom of it.
I take this badge off and get to the bottom of it.
I don't work for the law.
The law works for me.
I promise you.
I've been smelling something in this department for a long time.
And I'm going to get to the bottom of this shit.
Oh, no.
What the hell was that?
What is that?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
What are you doing?
I'm saving you, amigo.
Don't worry.
Freeze, goddammit.
Don't you even think about it.
Stop this car right now.
It's an old fashioned escape mission, buddy.
Stop this car.
What the fuck are you doing?
Oh, shit.
What are you doing?
Oh, shit!
It's the lady club!
That's the murderer!
Oh, God!
What?
That's the lady club!
What do you mean?
Then who's that?
I don't know!
Oh, shit!
They're shooting!
Oh, my God!
Fuck!
Shit, I can't see!
The slushie!
Turn on the wipers!
It's not working!
Don't kick out the window!
Isn't that what they do?
I don't know!
How do you drive with one foot?
Oh, man!
Oh, fuck!
I think I pulled my groin!
Get your foot out of there!
She's gaining on us, man!
She's behind us!
Her car's better!
Get your leg out of there, man!
Seriously!
I can't!
Put her in a maximum overdrive!
Ah!
Oh, no, no, no, no!
Oh, no!
Oh, shit!
Ow!
Just get it out!
Ow, ow, ow!
Ow, my foot!
Jesus, I can't see!
Ow!
Whoa!
Danger!
Trees!
Tree!
Squirrel!
Hey, I can see through my leg hole.
Nice, nice!
Look out, look out!
Tree, tree, tree, tree!
Cut it, cut it, cut it!
You did it, man!
All right!
Look out!
Oh, shit!
Shit!
I'm scared, Saul.
I'm scared.
Don't worry, man.
I'm handling this.
Well, do something!
All right.
Hold on.
I got an idea.
Oh shit!
Go, go, go, go!
Sorry!
What the fuck was that?
Fuck or shit, I'm sorry.
I thought you'd just go past.
Why?
I don't know.
What?
Oh, my.
Wow.
Yes!
Yes, we made it!
All right, man!
All right, Amigo, let's get the fuck out of here!
No!
No, what are you doing?
You forgot me, you idiot!
Come back!
Stupid.
So!
I'm sorry, man.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
All right, let's go.
No, wait!
Get the handcuff keys, you idiot!
Now!
As soon as we kill those sacks of shit tonight, Ted,
I'm moving on.
OK.
All right.
And I promise you, you're going to be taken care of.
Yeah.
You sure shit, you will.
But for now, this is what we're going to do.
We're going to go to the farm tonight.
We're going to move tonight's shipment.
And then the first thing tomorrow morning, we are going to hunt these guys down.
Dale, Saul, the Asians, every last one of them.
We're going to fucking kill them all.
So smile.
Shut up.
Say something in Spanish.
Go ahead.
I dare you.
All right, well, are you using protection?
I know you're using protection.
Oh, yes.
May I have the garage, Leroy, please?
Hello?
Hello, is Angie there?
Dale!
Angie?
Oh my God, are you okay?
I'm good.
I'm fine.
I'm great.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Okay, good.
I came up with a plan.
Okay, it might sound weird at first, but just listen.
You know what?
Drug dealers, let me just tell you something.
Drug dealers are trying to kill me and you and my family.
I can't believe I'm in this situation right now because
and your addiction to marijuana.
I cannot believe I'm here.
Can't be addicted to marijuana.
A, I use a bong.
It filters out the addictive shit.
Seriously.
B, what the fuck does that have to do with anything?
I went in to murder Angie, and now I'm dealing with it.
This that's happening between us, this is normal.
This happens to every couple who's been dating for three months, and we just have to work through it.
No, it doesn't, Dale.
This doesn't happen to anyone.
I should not be in this situation, so fuck you.
You know what?
It's over.
Good.
Fine.
Whatever.
It's over.
Congratulations.
Had to happen sometime, right?
Why not now?
What the fuck does that mean?
It means that you are gonna go to college next year.
You'll get into Godspeed, you black emperor, and the fucking shins, and you'll blow a bunch of dudes, and you'll become a lesbian, and I'll be here in fucking Clark County doing shit all.
You're gonna dump me, so fuck it.
Have a good time.
A lesbian?
Fuck you, Dale.
You never did it like me anyway, did you?
You didn't even want to meet my parents.
I always cared about you.
That's not what this is ever, okay?
I always care about you, Angie.
Why do you ever act like it, huh?
Why do you never act like you care about anything?
Because I'm high!
Fuck!
And it... What do you want?
Okay, Jesus.
Call me when I can go home.
You lost a plane bid with?
You pimp.
No, I'll give you more, but you cannot gamble with it.
I'm sorry about the clocks.
I couldn't remember if it was today or tomorrow.
All right, I gotta go.
I love you.
You wise ass.
Hey, you all right, man?
Sounded pretty hectic.
I'm OK.
Let's just get the fuck out of here, OK?
All right.
First things first.
Don't.
Do that, okay?
Yeah, why not?
Why not?
Car chase, gunshots, that clearly just happened because we were smoking marijuana.
No, man, that happened because those fucking kids couldn't keep their shit on the down low, man.
In case you haven't noticed, which you haven't, because from what I can tell, you don't notice anything ever, we are not very functional when we're high, which is all the fucking time.
Well, I don't know, man.
I think I'm functioning right now.
I was, like, stoned when I saved you with those slushies.
What do you got to say to that, man?
Okay, well, that would be true if you had saved me.
But you didn't save me.
She was gonna help us, and you made things worse.
Now we're wanted for all sorts of fucking crazy shit.
Don't fucking get on my case, all right?
Look.
Only reason I started selling pot is so I could put my bubby in a nice retirement home.
Oh, yeah, she must be proud of you for that.
She is really proud of me, and I'm gonna become something, man.
As soon as she dies, I'm gonna become a civil engineer.
I'm gonna design septic tanks for playgrounds.
Little kids can take shits.
You idiot, what the hell do you do?
What I'm gonna do, besides staying in my home for fear that you've designed some object I'm around, I'm gonna be on the radio talking about life.
Ho-ho!
Giving lessons about life.
Well, me and my place.
I'm gonna be designing buildings, and what's he gonna be doing?
Boring people death on the radio.
You are an asshole.
That's all you are.
You're an asshole.
I'm not an asshole.
You are an asshole.
You know what?
I feel pretty sure that I'm not an asshole.
I'm, like, a totally nice guy.
I'm just as nice as you are, so you don't bring that out.
When we were in the woods, I gave you my jacket.
You were cold, and I clothed you.
How about in the park when I said that you were my friend?
You didn't say anything back.
Well, that's easy.
It's because we're not friends.
You are my drug dealer.
There's one reason we know each other.
I like the drugs you sell.
That's it.
If you didn't sell those drugs, I would have no idea who you were, and I would be fantastic right now!
Instead of looking like this!
That sounded mean.
Just hearing it sounded mean.
I didn't mean to say all that.
It's out, bro.
Monkey's out of the bottle, man.
What?
That's not even an expression.
Pandora doesn't go back in the box.
He only comes out.
I'm sorry, man.
Look, what are you doing?
Here.
Have a nice last meal.
Come on, man.
Don't do that.
Why don't you supersize it, bitch?
I'm sorry, man.
Look, come back.
I didn't mean that.
Ha ha ha!
That looks great.
Hello?
Dale?
It is Dale.
Angie, I'm calling because I love you more than anything in the world, and I want to let you know I'll do anything to make it work.
I'll do anything.
I've had a near-death experience, and when that happens, you can prioritize your life, and you are it, okay?
So please just take me back.
Please.
I love you.
Yeah?
I just don't want to lose you, Dad.
We were driving away from the house and I just kept thinking, I don't know, I just, I want to marry you.
Oh, I made a mistake.
What do you mean?
I have... What?
I'm just processing that last bit.
You want to, oh, fuck.
What?
I don't know.
I realize now that if you would take me back, then you are very naive and immature.
You don't see what a fuck-up I am.
I'm in no shape to be dated by anyone.
You're the one that's immature.
No way.
I'm not immature.
You're immature.
I mean, I am somewhat immature, but you're more immature.
I'm older.
Ugh, just because you're older.
You know what?
I lost my virginity when I was 14 years old.
Really?
How many girls have you even slept with?
Like two and a half?
Two and a half?
What is a half?
Your hand?
That doesn't count.
It was the tipper.
I dipped a ball in.
I can't remember why.
I just remember thinking, this doesn't count as a full point.
If I said three, I'd feel like a liar.
I don't know why.
I was drunk.
Screw you.
Just get me out of this motel room.
I will.
And that's the last you'll ever hear from me, OK?
Hey, Belogus.
Look at there, look at there, look at there.
So do you use the pool over here?
I don't play games.
Yes, I use the pool.
Come on, what do you want from me?
We need your grandson.
We need you to get on the phone with your grandson.
What are you talking about, my grandson?
You told me you want to sit down and play dominoes with me, and now you're hocking me about my grandson?
Is that Yiddish?
Yes, yes, it is.
May I call you Fay?
You can call me Fay, but I'm going to call you Singer.
Hey, Mrs. Mendelsohn, what do you want from me?
Bobby, hey, guys.
Oh.
Hello, baby.
Holy.
Back up.
Oh, damn.
Shit.
Damn.
THEY KIDNAPPED MY GRANDSON.
THESE TWO GUYS CAME IN.
THEY SAT DOWN WITH ME TO PLAY DOMINOES.
I NEVER SAW THEM IN MY LIFE BEFORE.
AND THEY KEPT ASKING QUESTIONS ABOUT MY GRANDSON.
WHAT DID THEY LOOK LIKE?
Well, one of them was very tall and sloppy.
And they wore black clothes.
And the other guy, he was very good looking, but he was short as shit.
But the worst part was that my grandson came in white and in pajamas.
Well, you've got to find my grandson.
We'll do the best.
I promise, ma'am.
Absolutely.
You've got something there.
I believe that's a mole, ma'am.
Oh, you sack of shit.
You know what a pain in the ass you've been.
Come on, man.
I don't want to get out.
Hey, hey.
Let's go.
Where am I, man?
What, man?
You guys started it, man.
I don't even want to be here.
Did I do that?
Oh!
Hey, hey.
Ow!
Hey, hey, hey!
Motherfucker!
I threw you, man!
Stand back.
What?
Ted wants him alive.
Why are you holding me back?
Ted wants him alive, OK?
I should be kicking his fucking teeth, then.
If anybody's going to beat him up, it's going to be Ted.
I look like Hamburglar.
I ain't an elephant man.
Look, someone fucked you up with a coffee pot, man.
Professional.
Professional on this, bitch.
Whatever, man.
And where were you?
I was there.
You were supposed to be my partner.
No, you wasn't there.
How did this happen then?
I take the hit.
That's how it's going to be?
Fuck all this, you know?
Get him out of here.
Take him downstairs.
Get this asshole out of my sight and out of my sight.
I don't want to go near this guy.
What's down there?
Fucking Rancor?
I might act tough.
I got a lot of feelings, and you hurt damn near every one of them.
This ain't over.
You know you're going to die, right?
Yeah.
I'm going to kill the fuck out of you.
I hope you enjoy these last 17 minutes of your life, because when Ted get here, he going to be like, kill that motherfucker.
I'm going to kill your motherfucker.
Watch your head.
Hey, watch him.
El Dorado.
The legends are true.
Look at all this weed, man.
What's that?
Purple granddaddy?
Come on.
Purple nurple?
OG Kush?
OG Kush.
It's the most beautiful thing I've ever seen.
What kind of irrigation?
Shut up.
Can I touch it?
Come here.
Hello?
Red?
Red.
What the fuck?
Get out of here, man.
I didn't do shit, Denton.
Look, I come in peace, okay?
I'm not here to fight you again.
Good.
Because I'm tired, man.
I'm feeling so hot.
You don't look great.
They shot me, Denton.
You got me right here.
Yeah?
Right here.
And then they got me again right here.
Look, man, I'll call 911 right now.
They'll save your life, okay?
You don't need to die.
No, bro.
You don't get it, man.
It doesn't really matter where I'm at.
If I'm at the hospital, if I'm here, Ted's gonna find me, man.
He will.
And when he does, he's gonna fucking kill me.
He's just like an asshole.
I couldn't agree more, Red.
That's why I've come here, okay?
You know, Ted, he took Saul, and I'm going to get him back.
You know, like, he saved my life.
We've been on the run together, and he's a great friend.
He's a good guy.
He is, man.
I'll tell you that, man.
Saul is a good dude.
And I was mean to him, man.
I wronged him, and I can't let it end like that.
Man, I'm just into Buddhism, and I'm at peace with the fact that me as this person...
probably gonna not be around.
Think about a hermit crab, okay?
And it's a shell and it's like, they go from one shell to the next.
And that's what I am.
It's like, I'm just a hermit crab changing shells.
Except if you're a dick your whole life, your next shell will be made of shit, okay?
If you're an asshole, you're gonna come back as a cockroach or a worm or a fucking anal bead, okay?
If you're a man and you act heroic, you'll come back as an eagle.
You'll come back as a dragon.
You'll come back as Jude Law.
Okay?
Which would you rather be?
Maybe the anal bead.
Depending on who it belongs to.
Belongs to me.
Then the dragon.
Exactly.
You need to help me, okay?
Just use it, you know?
Use the pain.
You'll have a second wind, man.
Let's just get up.
We can go get Saul back.
Use it.
Aren't you angry at Ted?
Yeah, I'm really mad at him.
Well, what do you want to do about it?
Don't you want to get up and do something about it?
Maybe.
Maybe that would be cool to do to him.
I don't think maybe is the answer I'm looking for.
I think yes.
I'm going to help you, Dale.
That's the answer I'm looking for.
Come here.
Ted Jones messed with the wrong melon farmers.
Thug life.
Oh, shit.
Just make sure you get those.
I don't want to run them over in the vacuum cleaner and shoot my face off, OK?
I'm sorry.
I used to use this little gun when I was a prostitute.
Don't.
Just something quick like that.
Yeah.
Don't.
Stop it.
You stop it right now.
Oh, God.
That's a big heart.
I can't do this.
I'm sorry, man.
I'm infected.
My shit's all fucked up.
I need medical attention.
What do you mean you can't?
I thought we just got all pumped up.
What was that all about?
Dude, Ted is a fucking murderer.
I can't fuck with him.
I got a wife, man.
She's going to be out of jail soon.
I want to fuck her.
I want to have sex with her.
I'm not going to wake up murdered tomorrow.
Oh, man, no.
This is lame of you, man.
I'm really sorry, dude.
I'm sorry.
Come on.
This could be your moment of redemption.
Fuck that.
This could be your moment.
I don't want a moment.
I'm not getting fucking killed.
You know what?
Fine.
Go.
Fuck you.
Please come back for me.
Please come back.
Carol, she's cool now, but Carol used to be a little crazy, man.
She used to throw tickle parties.
Sounds like home cooking to me.
That was fun.
Game over, motherfuckers!
Everybody freeze!
Tell me where my friend is and this guy gets it!
All right, everybody be cool, man.
Be cool.
Put your guns down.
Nobody's shoes.
That's right.
Put him down on the ground.
All right, everybody just chill.
Oh, my God, you shot him!
Put the fucking gun down!
Drop the fucking gun!
Okay, don't shoot me!
Holy shit!
I said nobody shoot.
You shot Pete.
That's right, I shot him.
I shot him, okay?
I shot him.
I don't have time for a fucking negotiation.
Now, I want to finish this shit off so I can go home and have dinner with my wife for once.
If anybody asks, Denton killed Pete.
End of story!
I'm talented.
If you do... He's got a piece.
Okay, I'm sorry.
Oh, I got another one right in the side.
Damn it.
Okay.
I got one more in my leg.
There's one more.
I know you'll find it.
Just take it.
I'm sorry, guys.
Sorry I deceived you.
No.
Come on.
Oh, great.
Saul.
Dale.
Yes.
What'd you do?
Rap me out?
Is that what you did, you bastard?
No, man.
Yes.
I'm here to save you.
No, you just got caught too.
I'm going to die in here with some asshole.
Okay, you know what?
I deserve that.
I'll take that because I have been an asshole, man.
This whole thing is my fault.
I ruined your life, okay?
And I know there's no way to make that up to you except by saving your life.
So that's what I came here to do.
I'm here to save my best friend because that's what you are, man.
You're my best friend.
You're a mean jerk.
I was mean because I think I didn't... I didn't want you to be my best friend.
I didn't want to think that that's what my life was.
But now I realize I'm lucky to have you as my best friend, man.
You're the best guy I know.
BFFF?
Best fucking friends forever, man.
Seriously.
Yeah, okay.
Thanks, man.
I'm so sorry about everything.
Oh, I'm such a dick.
Okay, I'm gonna get us out of here.
No, you're not, but it's okay.
Seriously, these guys are gonna fucking kill us.
We gotta get out of here.
No, they are.
Why the fuck, man?
We can hear you outside, and it's very fucking annoying, all right?
Okay, sorry about that, sir.
Shut the fuck up!
Do you know what shut the fuck up means?
I do.
Shit, you motherfuckers.
Yes.
Okay.
I got an idea.
My belt buckle.
Right here.
Okay?
Rub your wrist against my belt buckle.
That'll do it.
Yeah.
Is it working?
I can't feel it.
Yeah, I can't feel you.
Oh, wait.
I feel it.
I feel it a bit.
Yes.
Okay.
I'm going to save you, man.
Yeah.
Let me save you.
Save me, dude.
It's not working.
Okay.
Wait.
We've got to change angles.
Here.
We've got to get more limpergy.
Okay?
Wait.
Yes.
I'm gonna save you, man.
I'm gonna save you.
You're my best friend, man.
It's not working.
Let me use my mouth.
I'll use my mouth.
That'll do it.
Finish it off with my mouth, pal.
Let's go.
Come on.
Where are these fuckers?
We got them downstairs.
Where'd you find them?
We found Saul at his grandmother's.
He fucked up Matheson's face, hit him with a pot of hot coffee.
It's gross.
Dale Denton comes flying in here like a madman, armed to the teeth.
And as you can see, he shot Peter, plugged him, just whacked him.
And now they're both disarmed and they're downstairs.
He shot Pete?
Fucking Pete?
He was ex-CIA.
Who the fuck is this Dale Denton?
Who is he?
Where did he come from?
I do not know.
No retreat, no surrender.
Yes, yes, yes.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
If I cough once, I'll take the lead.
If I cough twice, you go, okay?
I cough sometimes.
Just don't, don't.
Mm-hmm.
Yo, look, I'm gonna say this one time.
Whatever you're doing, I get it, okay?
Stop!
See, I don't think you understood me.
I can hear everything you're saying out there.
One cough, me and you go.
Two cough, me and you take the lead.
The belt buckle, best friends forever.
Y'all fuck on your own time, man.
Sorry, man.
It was some stupid plan.
What the fuck is that?
You burned my face, huh?
Tear this ass up.
You shot me.
I'm sorry, man.
I ain't never been shot.
Damn, that hurt.
I got glass in my ass.
Damn.
Oh, that's messed up.
Damn!
Has anyone seen my bigger knife?
Kill them!
Kill them all!
Dale, no!
No, wake up, man!
No, you're not dying, man!
Not without me!
Dale!
What?
You're alive!
What happened?
He got your ear, man.
He got my what?
He got your ear!
Ow!
Fuck!
Oh!
Help!
My ear!
Yeah.
Help!
You killed my ear!
You shot me!
I didn't do that.
He shot me!
You shot him?
Get your hands off me!
Shut up!
We got enough out of you.
I'm not your friend.
Maybe I can just... No.
No.
Infected.
Is that it?
Maybe we just hold it.
Dude, look.
Nice.
Big ones.
So seriously,
How gross does my ear look?
Is it really disgusting or is it, like, kind of cool in a way?
Right now, it's pretty disgusting.
I feel like I can smell it.
Oh.
Don't worry, bro.
Think about what Vanderholy feel.
You can't even tell.
That's a good point.
Did you shoot that guy?
No.
He wanted bullets.
Me too.
Maybe it was ricochet.
Gravity.
Oh, nice.
You go down.
I'll cover.
Watch my back.
I'll go down and take care of this.
Sexy mother fucker.
No, no, there might be more mad guys up there.
We'll sneak out through the vent.
Come on.
I'll boost you up, okay?
And then you pull me up, okay?
Okay.
Here we go.
Get up.
Yeah.
Nice.
Okay.
Pull me up.
I'm ready.
Go.
Give it to me.
Come on.
Be taller.
Be stronger.
I can't get it.
Pull harder.
Yeah, come on.
Pull.
Pull me.
Come on, man.
I'm jumping as high as I can.
Hey, dead.
I'll get help.
Go ahead and run, you little dipshit.
I'll find you.
No!
Shit!
You and me, baby!
Drop it now!
Put the bag down!
Now!
Fuck you!
Fuck the police!
Why are you doing this to me?
Come on, I'll twist a ball so tight.
You're in the jungle now, baby.
Ow!
Jesus!
You weren't gonna stop.
Shoot him!
Just take it easy, buddy.
Shoot him, you dumb fuck!
I'm hungry.
I'm going home.
All right.
I knew you going soft.
Dinner's going to be cold tonight, asshole.
Fucked up, man.
Well, lookie here, Mr. Folgers.
What's up, Sal?
Look, I didn't want to hit you, man.
Shut the fuck up!
You think you was going to get me, motherfucker?
Huh?
You need to sit your little sexy ass down and watch yourself get killed now.
All right.
You know what?
This is how it's going to be.
All right.
This is how it ends.
You just got killed by a de Wulanos, motherfucker.
How you like me now, huh?
Gross.
Red?
Saul.
Hey, Saul.
I came back for you, bro.
Yeah.
I remembered, man.
Bros before hoes.
You lied to me.
I did.
I lied big time to you.
Dale said that...
You didn't even have herpes, and I said that you did.
Honestly, like, from now on, just, like, from everything that we've gone through, and, like, from seeing this fucking asshole's nuts smashed with my Daewoo, I just, I want to be a better friend to you.
Like, I really am.
I fucking love you, dog.
I fucking love you.
I want to be inside you, Holmes.
No more lies, Red.
This is my moment.
This is your moment.
Red!
You know what?
I'm feeling it.
Red, I'm coming, baby.
Your stupidity amazes me.
Hey, Ted!
You will kill my brother!
Caucasian son of cocksucker!
Suck my balls!
Two times!
Bitch!
Bring it on.
Damn!
Oh, shit!
Sorry, Ted.
But you've been served.
Oh, shit!
Sol!
Wake up, man!
The space is gonna collapse!
Come on!
Come to me!
You're not dying today, friend.
Not on my watch!
Saul!
Wake up, man, please!
Wake up!
Oh, sweet Saul.
Saul!
Saul, you made it.
What?
Yeah.
You made it, man.
You saved me.
You came back for me.
Yeah.
Oh, thank you.
What happened?
Holy shit.
Hi.
Fred?
Fred.
Where'd you come from, man?
Where'd he come from?
He came back to save us.
He saved us?
Yeah.
That's right, man.
We all saved each other.
Yeah.
Oh, man.
We made it, guys.
We made it.
Hello, you're listening to PPR PPP.
I am Dale Denton.
The topic of the day, new beginnings, getting over losses, friends, life.
We have our first caller.
Yes, ring, ring, ring.
How's it going?
Hi.
Am I on the air?
You are.
You're about to get D'd by the Dale.
A D in the face.
Dale Denton.
Yeah.
You're my hero.
Yay!
You are good, man.
Seriously.
Thanks, man.
I gotta admit, yeah.
It sounds pretty good.
It sounds real, dude.
It's not bad, huh?
If I close my eyes, it does sound like it.
Yeah, that's the voice.
You are on the radio.
That's the radio.
This is the radio.
That's the DJ.
No, but better.
Like, if you were on it, I would listen to it.
Thanks, man.
It's like when my bubby was always playing opera, I was like, I hated it, but my bubby loves it.
And it grows on you.
Yeah, it grows on you.
That's nice.
It's like Red.
I didn't like Red when I first met him, I'll be honest.
You didn't like me?
No, but you liked him so much, I like you now.
I know this sounds weird, but can we be best friends?
Just us, for real?
I think we should all be best friends.
We should be.
You guys are my best friends.
Seriously, man.
We shared a moment.
You guys were like both of my best friends, and you didn't even know it, but now you know it, and we'll all be best friends.
You know what we should get?
You know those hearts that break up, and it's like best friends?
We should get like a three-way one of those, man.
I don't even know if they fucking make those.
We should make the first one.
We should make three-way.
What about three?
I want the middle piece that'll be crooked on both sides.
I know we've gone over this again and again, but like, a thousand pardons, a thousand pardons, please.
Me too, man.
I was a dick to you, man.
I'm sorry.
I know that I was an asshole.
I hope I redeem myself with you.
And I know me and you have had our deal.
We've had some times now.
But I kind of feel like something's happening here.
I think it's growing.
Was that a boner?
Is that a condo?
Is that us moving into an apartment together?
Is that us getting a timeshare?
You threw an ashtray in his face.
You hit me, man.
At the time, I was like, whoa, but I was kind of funny.
You hit me with the dust buster, man.
I didn't want to hurt you, but it was like, you better fucking not leave here.
That was such a good fight, man.
That was.
You fucking... Yeah.
The car chase was pretty awesome.
You guys had no fucking car chase.
Yeah.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Yeah, it was pretty good.
Oh, my God.
I, like, had my foot through the window.
My groin, I mean, I felt like a wishbone.
I'm trying to decide how stoned I am and just how, like, on the verge of death am I right now.
It's like, am I, like, seeing shit because I'm stoned or because I, like, have no blood left in my body?
You've been shot, like, seven times.
You gotta eat, man.
You gotta eat.
You're losing stuff.
Yeah.
Here.
Yeah, okay.
We are fine.
Like a baby.
It's a miracle.
I think we should just all take a moment and think about what a miracle it is that we got out of there.
And that we all became friends in the process and like kind of learned some shit about life and stuff.
Should we put our hands together?
I love you guys.
Okay.
I love you dudes so much.
Red?
Red.
Yo, Ren, man.
You alive?
What's up, pal?
Uh-oh.
Hey.
I'm like the nerd at the sleepover.
It's okay.
We won't put our dicks in your mouth.
Oh, shit.
Oh, gosh.
Hey, there's Bubby.
Oh.
Clint.
Let's get out of here.
Yeah, you know what?
Maybe we should go to the doctor.
We go?
Oh, dude, do you think he'll drive me to the hospital?
Me too.
I should get the earmarked.
Yeah, we should both go.
My ear should probably get professional attention.
It is bad.
Whoa.
That's a bullet burp.
It's either I'm getting ready to die or I'm going to take a massive shit.
Somebody's going to get me to the hospital.
My ear keeps sticking to my shirt.
You guys smell like shit.
You are seriously.
Dude, if you're not dying from fucking machine guns.
Brother, grab your chillum and get on your gear.
We got problems.
We got to get out of here.
But I got you and you got me.
And we're as high as we can be.
So it's all right.
Oh, yeah, it's all right.
It's not your fault and it's not mine I was just in the wrong place and time Now there's trouble Oh yeah, trouble And how did we get into this mess?
Pineapple Express Pineapple Express
Oh, totally gone, cause we're on Pineapple Express.
Brother, keep your head down.
Be as cool as you can.
Know I got us, oh, a new evacuation plan.
Just say hello and follow me.
They can't see what we can see, cause we're on it.
Yeah, and it's the chronic.
Don't get excited.
Just get your head right.
We'll stick together if it takes all night.
But it's all right.
Yeah, it's all right.
And how did we get into this mess?
Pineapple Express.
Not used to the stress.
Righteously find the kind, Pineapple Express.
We're on the express, the best in the west.
And with the rest, it's the best, Pineapple Express.
And how will we get out of this mess?
Pineapple Express
Can't deal with this stress Totally gone, cause we're on Pineapple Express Get on the express Pineapple Express That is the best of the rest The Pineapple Express It's so fine
It's a kind pineapple express.