There's a legend that precedes the dawn of our civilization.
A vile god, so large and so powerful that it consumed entire planets as fuel.
Few believed such a thing could be true, until the day we saw Unicron with our own eyes.
He wanted our greatest technology.
The Transwarp Key.
And he sent his most powerful henchmen to collect it.
Scourge.
Power.
More enemies are landing.
We won't be safe for long.
Do we have the key?
You must take it.
Keep it hidden.
So that it never falls into the hands of Unicron.
But Ape Link, we can fight.
No.
Protecting our transwarp key is all that matters.
Go!
Use it to escape!
What will you do?
I'll hold him off.
buy you some time.
Then I'm staying with you.
This is my fight.
Listen.
If Unicron were to get the key, he could open a portal through time and space with no end to the worlds he could destroy.
It is now your time to lead the Maximals.
Optimus.
Primal.
So you're this planet's great warrior.
You have such a beautiful world.
Filled with an abundance of life.
Savory.
We'd rather die than let him breach other planets.
So be it.
Benefits of serving the almighty Unicron.
They never learn.
You're too late, Scourge.
Your master will be trapped in this galaxy forever.
No.
His sacrifice will be our oath.
To preserve the key, no matter the cost.
When you acquire the key, use it to bring me to you.
We'll be right back.
Show me the money.
Here we go.
Yo, Sonic.
Breakfast ready yet?
I ain't your butler, Chris.
Come on, man.
No names over the airways.
It's tails.
Oh, my bad.
Christopher Diaz from 974 Wilson Avenue, apartment 2C, Brooklyn.
Ain't no secret government agencies worried about us tails.
Now get your behind out here while it's hot.
At least I got that going for him.
Here, I ironed this for you.
I already ironed it.
Like you cooked those eggs?
What you mean?
It's just seasoned.
I can't get past Bowser.
Good morning to you, too.
Drink this and take your medicine.
All of it.
Are you sure you can take them?
Yeah.
Hospital's on the way.
I got time.
That lady, that administrator is there, and she mentions a bill.
Just tell her we're handling it.
I will.
And after today, I'll be able to help out more.
Good luck on the interview.
Don't forget to laugh at all the jokes.
White people love that shit.
Ma, language.
OK.
Remember, I have class tonight, so I'll be home late.
Lo quiero.
I love you.
Hurry up, man.
We got to get into the city.
Hey, hold up, hold up.
Your hand's hurting again?
No, it's nothing.
Let me see.
Chris.
It's falling.
Sickle cells must be blocking the blood flow again.
How long has this been going on?
Couple days.
Yo, look, I told you.
You gotta tell me these things.
You fighting this alone or you fighting it together?
Together.
On team?
On team.
Two foot ten.
Two foot... Stop touching everything.
Oh, hell no.
Hey, yo, Chris, what'd I tell you about letting your mans come out the crib looking like a whole square?
It means so much I could do.
Yeah, all right, whatever, bro.
Look.
Here.
My dog.
When you gonna let me put your skills to work and get you some real money?
Yeah, says the dude who can't even afford cable.
Hit the guy who don't wanna win.
I choose not to purchase cable.
It's my own personal way to protest the vampiric nature of modern-day capitalism.
that interview in that dusty suit.
I'm coming.
Hey, guys.
That's a good one, but the ankylosaurus is an armored dinosaur.
Oh, and that is absolutely a Roman.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Thank you for being patient.
Intern.
Intern, I paged you three times.
Why didn't you call me?
Okay, well, I figured if I stopped the call, that would make me later.
The police are here.
They busted an art auction.
The owner claims that everything is authentic, but they want a second opinion.
All right.
The Da Vinci sketch is legit.
The painting's a copy.
We're the ones at the National Gallery in London.
Roman vase.
Valuable, but you are not gonna retire off of it.
And this Greek curse tablet, it would be expensive, but it's a fake.
How can you tell?
See the spelling?
Roman.
Doesn't even show up in that era.
Got it.
Officers, I figured it out.
So, the da Vinci, that is real.
Now, where did you come from?
What are you?
It's pretty neat, right?
Yes.
Where is it from?
They just discovered it in Sudan.
The boys say it's Horus, 5th millennia BC Nubian.
This symbol is definitely not hieroglyphic.
Well, if it's as exotic as it looks, I'm gonna get a feature in Minerva.
Jillian.
Okay, team.
Let's do it.
Okay, what are the rules?
Rules before hoes.
Don't be a problem.
Don't go looking for a problem.
Or else we're gonna have a problem.
I know, I know.
Okay, I'll be back in a little bit.
Mr. Diaz?
Hey, I know we're a little behind on the bill.
Three months behind, and until your account is current, you can't bring your brother here.
I've told you that.
I'm gonna fix it.
I just need a little more time.
You can always take him to the ER.
Well, they won't see him in the ER unless he's critical.
Mr. Diaz.
He's 11.
He's 11 years old.
Come on, Chris, we gotta go.
What happened?
I'll tell you later, man, all right?
Come on, let's get out of here.
Hey, y'all, sit here.
Don't move.
After a conference with Simpson's attorney, Howard Weitzman... Can I help you?
Yes, hey, I'm here for an interview with the head of security, Mr. Bishop.
I'm Noah Diaz.
It's been canceled.
No, no, that has to be a mistake.
Then write for Mr. Bishop.
Mr. Bishop, hey, hey!
It's okay, Walker.
Look, it's me, Noah Diaz.
Sir, I think your boy back there is confused.
He said our interview is canceled.
Because it is.
Wait, why?
On the phone you said I was perfect for the job.
You said this was just a formality.
It was until your own commanding officer called me back.
Said you were brave, an expert com tech, but unreliable.
Couldn't trust you.
Your head was always somewhere else.
Sir, I can't explain all of that.
I had some responsibilities at home.
My brother, he said... You had a responsibility to the United States Army.
Mr. Bishop, sir, I'm a hard worker, okay?
I just... I just really need a break.
Listen, I can't have someone like you mess up what I built.
Someone like me?
And you don't know anything about me.
I know you don't know how to be part of a team.
Hey, look, Superman went on a bunch of interviews before he got his job on the Daily Planet.
Man, he never gave up.
I'm not Superman, Chris.
Life ain't a comic book.
I'm just saying.
You'll get the next one.
Yo, there is no next one.
No one's coming to save us.
We're alone in this.
Hey, man, I'm sorry.
Sorry.
No, it's not.
None of this is.
You know what?
Come on.
Go ahead, bro.
Just head upstairs.
I'll be right there, all right?
So what were you talking about earlier?
Hey yo, you want one?
No, I don't want any candy.
You gotta relax, B.
Your energy is really affecting my chi, and I get it.
I was nervous my first time too, but you might want to do some breathing exercises or something.
Look at me.
My man, my man, my man, my man.
It's just, I ain't done this before.
I know that.
But them rich cats in there, they give a ton of paper to charities every year to make themselves feel better.
Hell, if you look at it from a holistic perspective, we doing them a favor.
Hey, yo, you woke!
Yo, will you stop?
What are you doing?
This ain't about to affect they pockets at all.
And it's about to be easy as hell.
So why you ain't the one going in there doing it?
Because, Papito, I'm the mastermind.
Now, come on.
Weakness in your ear.
My man, you serious?
Yo, is that even clean?
It's the fourth quarter.
We got about 10 seconds left on the clock, and you got the ride.
Hey, man!
Don't slam the door.
Okay, I am off to my fundraiser.
What do you think?
It's nice.
Um, can I... can I ask something about you?
So, I've been doing some research, and I don't think that the statuette is Horace.
As a matter of fact, I'm sure it's not.
The boys dated it around 5,000 BC, right?
Mm-hmm.
But the Nubians, they never even had contact with the Egyptians until 600 years after that.
The symbol's not hieroglyphic.
I don't even think it's from that part of the world.
I think it might be Aztec or Inca.
It's not some Egyptian god.
It's something else.
Interesting.
Get those pressed, OK?
There you go.
Let that breath fill you up.
In, out.
Please stop talking.
Okay, all right, I get it.
You don't like to chit chat back and forth, but I got something for you.
You got a Robin mixtape?
No, I got a Liberating mixtape.
Feeling that, huh?
Yeah, whatever.
All right, there shouldn't be nobody in this part of the building.
You should be able to just waltz right on in.
Strike one, mastermind.
This place is packed.
Hey, well, to ever is divine.
Just act like you own the place.
Hey, what's up, brother?
Good to see you again.
Try not to look suspicious.
Here you go.
Sorry, sorry.
That's you, bro.
And that's glasses.
I didn't know you had glasses.
What are you doing?
Making friends?
Everything good?
We're in a mix.
Hey, let's see what you really are.
Now my man said it's tucked in the back.
Been there a couple weeks.
It's like a grayish car with like a blue stripe.
All right, now just like Brother Reek showed you,
Down the window, a little wiggle, feel that snag, and now we making money.
All right, talk to me, homie.
I'm in.
This won't hurt a bit.
I'm gonna lose my job.
I'm gonna go to jail.
There's definitely not no being
Oh.
Calling all Autobots!
Yippee-ki-yay!
Prime, this is RC.
I have a visual.
What am I looking at?
A way home.
Calling all Autobots!
Well, hell, the coast is clear out here, so whenever you want to slide that thing on out, you good.
I can't.
Like you can't drive stick or something?
No, it's just, I ain't no thief.
Are you having an existential crisis now?
The deadline for that was when I offered you Twizzlers.
This is an emergency.
Can you hear me, Mirage?
Roll out.
Who the hell was that?
It's the radio, bro.
This car is bugging.
I'm out.
Hey!
Hey, you!
Get out of the car!
I'm trying!
The car started by itself!
I promise!
Look, it's not working!
Get on there!
Yo, look, we... What you doing?
No, what's... Ring!
Ring!
Now that's top-tier manifestation!
Yo, the car's driving by itself.
Noah, you good?
I don't know what's going on.
It won't stop.
Stop.
Why aren't you listening?
But you might want to slow down.
It's not me.
It's the car.
It's possessed.
No, no, no, no, no.
You're just on an adrenaline high.
Let's do some of them breathing exercises.
Yo, I don't need no breathing exercises.
The car's driving by itself.
Oh, snap.
Yo, Reek, what do we do?
No, I cannot hear you.
Frank!
No, I can't.
No, we did not!
No, you did not just leave me!
Pull over!
Help me!
Help!
Drive, drive, drive, drive, drive, drive!
The bridge!
Take to Williamsburg!
I got a 1037 in progress.
Silver Porsche.
Are you serious, man?
Oh, nah.
Yo, do something, please!
Ugh!
Yo, nah!
Nah, nah, nah, nah, nah, nah!
Come in, come in!
Can you hear me, Mirage?
What?
Yo, yo, yo, yo, slow down, slow down!
Whoo!
That felt good!
Get some oil pumping, you know!
Damn!
I've been cooped up forever, dude.
I can't tell you how old it gets.
Mirage, stay hidden!
Mirage, don't draw any attention to yourself!
Mirage, big is just a movie!
You'll never be a real boy!
But that was fun, man.
You're fun, dude.
Oh, right.
This is probably a lot for you, huh?
Back up!
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
That's with the aggression.
Well, I thought after the car chase we were boys.
You gonna hit me?
Maybe.
Just like that?
Hmm.
Tough guy.
I like that.
I like it a lot.
What are you?
Some sort of possessed car or something?
Nah, that's not real, man.
I'm an alien.
Like...
Like E.T.?
E.T.?
The little ugly guy in the basket?
Look at this face.
The name's Mirage.
Come on.
Give me a little... Give me a little... Give me a little... Give me a little tap.
Give me a little tap.
There you go.
Now we're friends.
Oh, great.
The gang's here.
They're more like you?
Like me?
No.
But be cool so they don't crush you.
What?
Yeah, I'd put that pipe down if I were you.
Oh well, soon we got here.
Mirage, what have you done?
You brought a human here?
Optimus, hey!
Looking good, man.
Wait a second, are those new rims?
You were told to stay hidden.
Right, right.
Crazy coincidence.
When you called all Optimus-like, Autobots, roll out!
This guy was already in the car, but he's cool, so it's cool, cool?
Not cool.
Who are you, human?
I'm nobody.
I ain't even seen nothing.
I'm not even seeing anything right now.
Arcee.
Private Noah Diaz, US Army.
Multiple commendations, a wizard with electronics.
Huh.
He's a soldier.
He does not look like a soldier.
I mean, you're looking pretty rough yourself.
Sorry, sir.
I will deal with your mistake later.
Okay, the energy surge we felt was in the 4,000 Yottahertz range, which is undetectable to humans.
I've reconstructed the source from the energy echoes.
I cannot believe it.
It exists, and it is here.
What the hell am I looking at?
The Transwarp Key.
It was thought to be lost thousands of years ago.
It was once used to open space-time portals to Energon-rich planets throughout the universe.
You mean Energon-rich planets?
Like... Cybertron.
After seven long years stranded on Earth, we finally found a way home.
We're to forget you, Rick.
Okay, so where is this Tran... Transwarp Key?
Thank you.
It's in the new museum on Ellis Island.
Let's blow it up!
Get the hell out of Dodge.
No, we can't just go in blasting and steal it, B. The humans will hunt us down.
What we need is a quiet way in.
Ooh, how about him?
No.
What?
Come on, man.
He can slip in right through one of them little doors.
Grab the key, leave a nice IOU, and peace out.
He's perfect.
What?
No, it is a bad idea.
I agree with Big Man.
So, it's been real, y'all, but... Uh, time out.
No, no, I know, I know.
Relax.
Let me just talk to my guy real quick.
Yo, don't leave me with these tight asses, bro.
We make a great team.
This is a waste of time.
Look, I'm not breaking in the museum for some space robots.
But what about for friendship?
Uh, uh, or, or, or... What about for cash?
Uh-huh.
You help us get this key so we can get off this rock.
No offense.
Love the neighborhood and all.
And then, I let you sell me.
Lambo?
Ferrari?
Indy?
Look, you get paid, and then I'll split.
So all I gotta do is walk in and out?
All you gotta do.
We'll take care of the rest.
Cross my spark and hope to die.
Wow, that was corny when I said it out loud.
And what about the big man?
Optimum or whatever?
You let me worry about him.
Cool?
Ah!
Got him!
He's in, baby!
Whoo!
So y'all are robots that transform into cars, even though you're from way out in space.
But now there's this key that opens a portal back to your home?
Oh, and you know this because there's a beacon light in the sky that I can't see because I'm human.
You say that like it's weird.
It's super weird.
You know what's weird?
Marky Mark is leaving the Funky Bunch.
I heard he's just gonna pursue acting now.
That's crazy.
What?
How does that even... What a world.
Whatever, man.
I'm just trying to collect this money and get your angry-ass boss off of Earth before he blows a gasket.
Don't take it personal.
He just misses home.
And I think he blamed himself for us getting stuck here.
Earth was supposed to be a pit stop, you know, a place for us to regroup and rejoin the war back home.
Prime feels like it's his fault we've been stranded here, like he has to fix it all on his own.
All right, team.
Heads up.
There's security up ahead.
Nice.
This is gonna be fun, man.
No, no, no, bro.
You need to switch it up.
You need to turn it to a helicopter or a speedboat or something.
I got something way better than that.
Good call.
I do not like this plan.
Yeah, Mirage isn't really known for being quiet.
At least Mirage is one of us.
We should not be relying on a human.
They are my friends.
I know one was good to you, B, but this is not our world.
The humans will always protect what is theirs.
We can only trust our own kind.
You can't handle the truth!
I do not want you going to that drive-in theater anymore.
Nightbird, search the island.
Finally, the hunt draws to a close.
Hello?
Back up, back up, back up!
I didn't think anyone was in here.
That's it.
Who are you?
Hm?
I'm, uh, the janitor.
To get out of here!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
You don't have to do that!
It's not what it looks like.
It looks like you're trying to steal museum property.
Okay, it's a little what it looks like.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
It doesn't belong to you anyway.
No, no, no, no.
Just stop.
Hey, hey, hey, look.
Relax, relax.
Let me explain.
It belongs to... to these... these giant robots from space.
Really?
Look, I'm gonna need that shit.
Get it off!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
What's going on here?
Don't move.
Ma'am, it's about time you showed up.
The key.
You're telling the truth.
Yeah, but those ones are with me.
Rip the flesh from their bones and bring me the key.
Here's yours.
Guys, we got company!
Autobots, protect the king!
Oh, they're flying now?
Who the hell are these guys?
Impossible.
I enjoy that look of confusion when an inferior being meets a higher power.
What the hell are those things?
Are you OK?
Hey, stop following me.
I'm not following you.
I'm just escaping in the same direction.
Run!
Go!
Scourge, I have eyes on the key.
Prime, I don't think we can hold these guys.
Oh, no!
Oh, my God.
Put me down.
Oh, that was so scary.
Oh, cool.
You're still alive.
Get the key.
Noah, get out of here.
Get off me!
I hate spiders!
Don't die!
The key!
Enough of these games.
I'll get it myself.
Not on my watch.
Aw, don't be frightened, humans.
This'll all be over soon.
And you call yourself a crime?
I'm tired of little things getting in my way.
Now to add a Prime to my collection.
Maximals.
Good.
Maybe we'll get a real fight.
No.
We got what we came for.
This cannot be.
We must go now.
Come with me.
have been me.
I'm sorry for your loss.
No offense, lady, but who are you again?
My name is Air Razor.
I am a Maximal, a warrior from both your past and future.
Oh, right.
That tracks.
Yeah.
We fled our whole planet on the eve of this destruction.
We sought refuge and hid here on Earth.
All right, so you're a Maximal.
Y'all are Autobots.
What was those things that attacked us earlier?
Terracons, servants of a dark, hungry god who feasts on entire worlds to sustain himself.
Unicron.
So you're saying this thing Unicron eats planets to survive?
Yes.
And he imbues his servants like Scourge with dark energy, which makes him all but invincible.
He is entirely beholden to Unicron.
Through his power, he possesses Scourge's soul.
Awaken, my Dark Master.
The galaxy will once again be yours to feast on, my master.
I should have gotten the key myself.
I should have known better than to rely on humans.
Hold up.
What, you blaming me?
After you conveniently left out the part about a planet-eating monster?
Because of you, Unicron will now use the key to consume every planet in the universe.
Including my homeworld.
He doesn't have the key.
At least, not all of it.
This is only half the key.
Please!
The Maximals!
They must have split it!
Excuses!
Complete the key, or else you will wish you had died with the rest of your planet.
We broke the key into two pieces for safekeeping, then splintered and went into hiding.
I do not know where the other half is.
For all I know, I am the last of our kind.
It's in Peru.
How you know that?
It's the symbols on the stone.
They were only ever recorded in one other place in the world, the Inca Temple of the Sun in Cusco.
It's one of the oldest buildings in the Western Hemisphere.
I'm guessing that that can't be a coincidence.
If you can track those symbols to Peru, so can the Terracons.
We need to get there before they do.
And then kill Scourge and take his piece to complete the key.
Yo, hold up.
Hold up.
You want to find this other key and deliver it to the guy that just kicked your asses?
The transwarp key is our only way home.
If this dude gets a hold of that thing, it's game over for Earth, our families, everybody.
I'm going.
Out of the question.
No offense, but I'm not trusting my home to a guy who couldn't even protect his.
It's my planet.
I'm going.
What about you?
Me?
What is your name?
Elena.
Elena, will you lead us to this temple?
Chance to stop the end of the world.
Actually, you'll be saving two worlds.
What are you doing up tails
It's too hot?
You playing that game too much.
Give it a rest, you know what I'm saying?
So your head can take a break.
I'm going to beat it.
My money's on you, bro.
We don't quit.
Come on, get some sleep, all right?
Yo, listen, I got to head out for a while.
And I don't know when I'm going to be back.
Why?
Oh, shit.
No, no, no, no.
Stop, stop, please.
Turn it off, turn it off.
What are you doing?
I told you to sit tight.
Stop it.
Turn it off, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I don't know what.
No, no, no, no.
Go back to bed.
Shut it off.
I told you to sit tight.
I got the bat.
Give me that.
Did he say bat?
You're going to wake up mom.
I know you're a robot.
Chris!
Yo!
You scratched my paint!
What are you doing?
Man, they didn't treat E.T.
like this.
You know this thing?
Yeah, we just...
Work friends.
Work friends?
You've been inside me.
Look, that thing I told you I have to go do, it's for him and his crew.
We're trying to stop the end of the world.
The world's ending?
No.
Maybe.
60-40.
You know I'm not gonna let that happen.
But that's why I have to leave.
I'll go get my things.
Tough kid.
What?
No.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold up, hold up.
You're not coming.
Why?
You need someone to watch your back.
It's too dangerous, Chris.
And I need you to stay here and take care of mom.
You might not come back.
Hey, robot.
Me?
What's up?
Watch out for my brother.
Okay?
You got it, little man.
Nah, I'm serious.
If he gets hurt, I'm coming after you.
Don't worry.
I got Noah's back.
I promise.
Mm-hmm.
On the team?
On the team.
Kids got heart.
Cajon is muy grande.
Wu-Tang is in the building, baby!
Way to be incognito.
Oh, come on, Prime.
Smile a little bit.
It won't hurt.
Let me see that underbite.
All right.
So what kind of jet we taking to Peru?
Or is it a plane?
Either one's fine.
I just need first class, OK?
Because I got long-ass legs.
Well, he is a plane.
No.
No, no.
Don't tell me we're flying on, oh, no.
My lads, I am Stratosphere, Lord of the Skies!
Yeah, I'm walking to Peru.
Chasing waterfalls.
Ooh.
Oh, my gosh.
Gonna have it your way or nothing at all.
But I think you're moving too fast.
Sorry.
I sing when I get nervous.
It usually calms me down.
First time flying?
And it's my first time leaving New York.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
So the Bronx, huh?
Brooklyn, all right?
East New York all day.
I'm from Bushwick.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Me and my dad, we used to go to this pizza spot down on Knickerbocker and Green.
Tony's Pizza?
Wow.
Tell me about your pops.
What was he like?
He was a cabbie for 40 years.
Smartest guy you ever met.
He can talk to you about anything.
History, science, cricket.
Cricket?
He ain't never even go to college either.
He used to always say, if you keep your eyes and your ears open, life will show you everything you need to know.
So that's why you say yes to all of this.
I figured if he is somewhere watching, then seeing his daughter do something crazy like this would definitely make him proud.
You really think this key thing is in parole?
I think so.
The evidence lines up.
If it is, and we get our hands on it, then we gotta destroy it.
What?
They can't unite the key without both pieces.
No key, no Unicron, no Earth getting eaten.
Yeah, but then they can't get home.
We gotta think about us.
All you gotta do is find it, and I'll take care of the rest.
Do you think an Energon infusion could bring him back?
Perhaps.
If we could get him back to Cybertron.
I never should have taken us so far from home.
Wow, Wheeljack needs to fix that power steering.
Sorry I'm late.
I was taking in a harmonious moment between a serene butterfly and an unruffled caterpillar.
Such tranquility.
Yo, oye, Papa, where you from?
Cybertron.
So where'd you get that accent?
Accent?
What accent?
You know what I'm saying?
I'm just saying it's cool.
Like, I was about to be like, yo, mira, Papi, de donde eres?
Pero I didn't want to assume that you speak Spanish, too.
Because then, right?
A little racist, hermano.
I'm not trying to be, you know, yo.
But anyway, the mission, follow me.
He's a robot, like, so how's that racist?
Okay, guys, check this out.
The coordinates you gave me correspond to an old church.
Take a look.
That's Santo Domingo.
The Spanish built it on top of an old Inca temple.
Correcto.
I picked up some residual energy readings around the courtyard, so I'm guessing the key's somewhere close by.
But we may have some trouble getting there.
In Tiraymi, it's a festival that shuts down the whole city.
Guess it's a night mission, then.
No.
Scourge could already be here.
We must retrieve the other half before he does.
Me and Elena will do it.
Y'all never make it two blocks.
There's human security all around the church.
You'll never get through.
Then we'll have to take a play out of your book.
We'll hide in plain sight.
We'll blend in with the parade.
It is not a bad idea.
We will keep an eye out for the Terracons.
On first sign of trouble, we are going in.
Yo, Noah, think fast.
And if you need help, just holler.
I am in position.
All right.
Coast is clear.
Noah, Elena, it's go time.
Blend in.
Act natural.
Autobots must be using their new pets to reach the temple.
Lovely.
They're doing our work for us.
Go fetch.
The key's gotta be in here somewhere.
That stonework is 17th century.
What we're looking for is... something... much, much older.
What is it?
It's the same insignia on Airazor.
But it's not lined up right.
Wait, you see that?
I think there's something under here.
There's another one.
Now where?
I thought it was here.
It's some Indiana Jones type shit.
You sure about this?
Nah.
Any sign of Scourge?
Nope.
All clear here.
Yeah, yeah.
It's just groupies over here.
Stay on task, Mirage.
Prime, you gotta learn how to relax, my man.
You know, we must be the first people to walk here in half a millennium.
Yo, Sonic, you dead yet?
No.
Wait, did you just call me Sonic?
I think that's a temple.
What are we looking for?
You see the symbols on that temple?
They match the ones in the courtyard.
I think it's up there.
I think we found what we came here for.
I always wondered what it would feel like to be there when artifacts were actually found.
Come on, push.
Are you even pushing?
Yeah, I'm pushing.
Oh, no, no, no.
Where is it?
Sometimes there's like a, like a false bottom or something.
Look, I think I found something.
You see these symbols?
I've seen markings like this.
The air is a statue at my museum.
They're new.
They're not on the transport key.
There's two of them.
Let's keep moving.
Give me a second.
Rush!
We got trouble!
One of our bases down here!
Where are you guys?
Hang tight!
I'm on the way!
The Autobots are moving.
They must have found the key.
Come on!
Airazor, where are the humans?
They're underground, heading towards the jungle.
Oh man, they're tailing us!
You want me to do?
Come on!
We had a gun this whole time.
No!
What the hell are you doing?
I'm going to take back Scourge's key and then take off his head.
Guys!
I could use a little help!
Did someone call for backup?
What?
Ray!
Yay!
This is for me!
Hold on!
I love your fire, Prime.
I can think of no better place to bury you.
I will end you, Scourge.
That is a promise.
They're getting away.
Not this time.
I hear water.
Where are we?
Who are you?
And why are you hunting for the key?
Yo, Donkey Kong, stay away from my friends!
Oh, Mirage!
Don't worry, your boy's got this.
Uh-oh!
Stranger danger!
Hey, hey, hey!
Not so fast!
Aye, aye, aye.
Hey, over here, kitty kitty.
Stand down!
Don't ask a second time.
No!
All of you, stop!
There it is.
Primal, I thought you were lost.
All of you.
The others, are they?
I am all that is left.
Prime, these are my fellow Maximals.
Rhinox.
Keetor.
Sorry about scaring you, brother.
Scared?
Please, I'm not scared.
That's just engine oil.
And our leader, Optimus Primal.
Optimus Primal?
Named after you, the legendary warrior of Cybertron.
It's an honor.
Eraser.
I'm happy to see you, old friend.
But bringing others here was not part of our plan.
I fear you bring dark tidings.
Scourge has come to Earth.
He's found us.
And he has half of the key.
We must find the second piece before he does.
But it wasn't in a cave.
It was.
But we moved it long ago to keep it safe.
Where is it now?
Come with me.
That doesn't look so good.
When Scourge touches you, he leaves a mark.
But I'll be all right.
Hey, back then you called me Sonic.
Yeah.
Your little bro's got this thing about using real names over the airwaves, so... You been talking to Chris?
Uh-huh.
He gave me this to keep tabs on you.
Make sure I'm keeping my promise.
Oh, here.
Next time include warning labels.
Nah, go ahead.
Keep it.
I guess it does look better on me.
Just don't ask what part of my body it came from.
So, who are you?
We Maximals are an advanced race, dedicated to the expansion of life throughout the universe.
We use the Transwarp Key to visit young worlds.
The Nazca lines?
The temple at Tikal?
That was you guys, right?
Not us.
We cannot claim credit for human ingenuity.
But you had the key.
Why stay on this world?
When Unicron destroyed our world, we took an oath dedicated to the preservation of life.
This is Amaru.
He and his family are the last descendants of a tribe that has watched over us for hundreds of years.
When we arrived, they shared their world with us, and together we protected its people and our secret.
You allied with humans.
We did.
If you give us this key, tomorrow I will light the beacon and bring Scourge to us.
The Maximals have already sacrificed one home to protect the universe.
I won't risk losing another.
As a leader, I know you understand.
He is not the Optimus Prime I imagined.
Well, he has lost so much.
If you had another chance to save our home, would you act any differently?
Optimus, come.
I want to show you something.
Your friend will find peace here.
This is raw energon.
I'm sorry, but in this state, it is inert.
It would take a great power to ignite it.
Greater than anything we have here.
I see that you are surprised we entrust the key to them.
Yes, I am.
I've been amongst them a long time now.
There is more to them than meets the eye.
They are worth saving.
What if we didn't destroy it?
Maybe there's another way to save both our homes.
Elena, I made a lot of mistakes in my life.
This is different.
I can't fail like this.
I can't let my family down.
You're just like him.
You know that?
Who?
Optimus.
I'm serious.
He feels it too.
Feels what?
Like a beast of burden, just trying to carry the weight of the world on his shoulders.
You'd think he's some general barking orders, but when I look at him, all I see is a big brother trying to protect his family.
Are you okay?
Here is it.
I can feel scared.
Peace in my mind.
Run, Helena!
No!
Airazor.
They found us.
Everyone, defensive position.
Noah, guard the key.
Take Elena and find someplace safe to hide.
We must protect the humans.
Miss me?
Noah!
Elena!
Get out of here!
We have to destroy it!
No!
Don't.
I know you want to protect your people.
But if you destroy that key, our home will be lost forever.
We do not have to choose.
Please, Noah.
Alayna!
Kill them.
Airazor, no!
I can't hold it back much longer.
Fight it, Airazor.
Remember our oath, Primal.
No matter the cost.
I can't hold it back!
Airazor, no!
This is okay.
Primal.
No matter the cost.
Alina, Alina, look at me.
Are you okay?
Scourge has the key.
Awaken, almighty Unicron.
Your time has come.
I am sorry, Gnaw.
We were looking out for your own.
I can't even be angry at you for that.
On my homeworld, we believe that the battle with darkness will continue till all are one.
I lost sight of that.
You fought for yours as I fought for mine, when we should have been fighting the darkness together.
But I ain't done fighting yet.
All right, everybody, squad up.
Bring it in.
There's got to be a way to stop this dude.
It's too late.
has more energy than a supernova.
Any interruption will ignite it like a bomb.
The only way to stop this process is an access code installed long ago as a safeguard.
OK.
What's the code then?
The code was split along with a key.
Sadly, the second half of that code died with Airazor.
No, wait, wait, wait.
I got it.
The one hiding her half of the key?
It had markings in it, just like the ones I found in the cave where you hid yours.
Together?
They must complete the access code.
So we got a chance now, right?
A slim chance.
That is all we need.
If you will show us the way, Primal.
All right.
We need to move quickly.
We have a small window before the portal opens large enough for Unicron to enter.
The bridge is girded by a series of tunnels.
They are too small for Maximals, but... But not for humans.
If Noah and Elena reach the central antenna, they can use the code to shut it down, remove the transwarp key, and close the portal before Unicron enters our atmosphere.
But Scourge will be watching our every move.
He'll do anything to stop us from getting the key.
Then we bring the fight to him.
Autobots and Maximals will charge the bridge together and lure Scourge onto the battlefield.
While me and Elena sneaking through the back way,
Sounds like we're all going to die.
If we are to die, then we will die fighting, all as one.
This world is yours, master.
Scourge?
They're back.
Prime... Protect the key.
Don't let them get to the bridge.
Maxables, Autobots, roll out!
Rhinox, Cheetor, maximize!
At least the foot soldiers took the bait.
Yeah, but Scourge didn't.
He's guarding the key.
All right.
This should lead to the bottom of the transwarp control panel.
Get the key, get the hell out of there.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to go distract Scourge.
You can't take on Scourge alone.
Relax.
A mirage, remember?
Hey.
Ah!
Take cover!
Someone give me a real fight!
It's a fight you want?
You got it!
What do we have here?
Elena, go!
Brave, but futile.
Hey!
Don't mess with my boy!
No one will remember this pathetic planet.
And no one will remember you.
Ross, what are you doing?
Keeping my promise.
Come on, you gotta get out!
It's okay, Noah.
Home.
Home team.
Kill the other human.
Ultron, you fought bravely, but this world is already mine.
It's too late.
Chris!
Noah?
What's going on?
Where's Mirage?
He's gone.
Gone?
No.
I'm sorry, Chris.
I'm not gonna win this one.
Well, you don't lose, right?
I wish that were true.
But I can't.
Yes, you can.
Nah.
Nah, man, I'm not you.
I hate being sick.
Whenever I wanna give up, you're always there telling me to keep going.
Well, now it's my turn.
Keep going, Noah.
You think you're nobody, but you're the strongest guy I know.
You guys, you're so cute.
For us, you're life.
Yeah, but I'm gonna need you to take the wheel.
He's my brother.
Noah Diaz.
From Wilson Avenue.
Apartment 2C, Brooklyn, New York.
No names over the airwaves.
Forget that.
Let him know who you are.
Yo, Scourge.
Remember me?
You think you can take me on alone?
He is not alone.
I'm never leaving Brooklyn again.
Oh, Energon.
Oh!
Run!
Noah!
I'm getting really tired of you humans.
You again.
You should have stayed dead!
I have come here to kick ass.
Glad to have you back.
Everyone, guard the bridge.
Elena, shut it down.
We gotta give her some cover.
We'll clear the way.
That's what I'm talking about.
100 Axes code.
How hard could that be?
You have got to be kidding me.
Just you and me, Scourge!
Let's end this once and for all!
Master, the reinforcements!
All right, I got this.
Let's go, B!
Say hello to my little friend!
We gotta hurry!
Last one.
Die, you ugly mother-
You will never see Unicron take this world!
You did it!
Brooklyn, baby!
No!
Unicron will prevail!
Later!
Time to show you the real power of the Prime!
This belongs to a friend of mine!
The panel... is destroyed.
I can't stop it.
Autobots, Maximals, retreat to safety.
I will destroy the key myself.
Prime, no!
There's got to be another way.
Be protect them.
Your sacrifice becomes our oath.
Thank you, my friends.
Everyone, on me!
Don't, Prime.
I can give you everything you want.
Then die!
Noah!
I got you!
Let me go, Noah!
Save yourself!
Still I I would!
Till all are one.
Bunch of Prime!
Yeah, baby!
Unicron, is he dead?
Trapped, but not dead.
Evil can never be vanquished completely.
He could return.
Let him come.
United, we will destroy him once and for all.
I am Optimus Prime, leader of the Autobots.
We have lost the Transwarp Key, and with it, our ability to go home.
But we have gained an ally in our battle against the forces of evil.
Forces too powerful for any of us to defeat on our own.
But together, we might just have a chance.
I am Noah Diaz.
What is there to know about me?
I was raised out in Brooklyn.
I got a little bro who calls me Sonic.
And if I gotta help save the universe in order to save the people I love, well then that's what I'm gonna do.
How you doing, sir?
I'm here for the job interview.
Noah Diaz.
I'll tell him you're here.
This Sunday on 60 Minutes, I sit down to talk with Elena Wallace.
She recently discovered an underground temple with a network of catacombs dating back to 5,000 BC.
I never could have imagined making the discovery of this significance.
So it's definitely a dream come true.
Brooklyn, baby.
They're ready for you.
Thanks, sir.
Elevator in the back.
Why don't you tell me about your strengths?
In addition to my experience with electronics, I've also been really developing my team-building skills, too.
That's all.
Look, I'm gonna be honest with you.
Resume's a little thin.
Yeah, well, I just recently had a job working internationally.
Oh, was that... No, don't think it's on here.
No, it was a short-term contract.
Oh, well, that's cool.
Why don't you tell me about that?
It was in South America.
So I got to work on my Spanish.
My mom was real happy about that.
You know moms.
She's just really... But while I was out there, honestly, man, it was really just like work, work, work, work, work.
That's a shame, because I heard the food is really good in Peru.
Yeah, I didn't mention anything about Peru.
Well, that's where you were, right?
I was... Down in Cusco?
With you and, uh, Elena?
And your, um... I don't know.
Calm friends?
What... What's going on here?
We know a lot about you, Mr. Diaz.
Who are you, like the CIA or FBI?
We are a secret government organization, strictly off the books.
We specialize in global threats, planetary loss prevention, that kind of thing.
We're in the middle of an ongoing war, and we'd love to have you join the fight.
You and your whole team.
Yeah.
The big guys.
No idea what you're talking about.
That's a good answer.
All right.
Either way, I want you to know, in lieu of the thanks of a grateful nation, we will be taking care of your brother Chris' health care.
All of it.
From now on, he will have 24-7 access to the greatest doctors in the world.
And these are doctors who don't ask their patients about account balances.
Are you serious?
Save the world, kid.
It's the least we can do.
I don't know what to say.
We'll work on that.
Your brother's gonna be just fine.
Oh.
Chris was right, by the way.
No names over the airwaves.
We could really use someone like you, Noah.
Why don't you think about it?
G.I.
Joe.
Come on, man.
Show me something.
That ought to do it.
This?
This is a complete waste of your skills and my expertise.
Think it came out pretty good?
Well, I guess we could call it modern art and sell it to some cats in Soho.
Nah, I'm not selling.
Is this about the five-hole thing?
I told you, I did not ditch you.
I was running to give and go.
I thought you knew the play.
All right, let's say I did ditch you, even though I didn't.
For your sake, I see your face.
Let's just say I did.
I think all the blood, sweat, and dead presents I put into getting these car parts for you make us even, Steven.
It's not that.
This car is special.
This car is a jigsaw puzzle made of garbage.
Here, I bet.
The joint don't even start.
Bet.
Yo, Mirage.
Woo-hoo-hoo!
Yeah!
Your boy is back!
This dude said I wasn't even gonna start.
What I've done...
Let's get it.
All the slander, all the banter, just one answer, I'm an animal.
I'm just one man, outstanding though.
Part wolf, part king, part Hannibal.
Example crews are built like I'm mechanical.
On the mic, I'm a cannibal.
You don't know who I'm family to.
You don't know my team.
You don't know what my man's a do.
Turn it up to the maximum.
Gorillas in the trap with them.
Got millions watching every move I make because I'm what's happening.
Got jaws dropping, autopsies.
Drop hard tops, got hard body.
This nine's totally our problem.
This high powered, high profit.
Yo.
Let's go.
What up, Dunn?
Let's get it.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, yeah, uh, yo.
Thank you.
you
So,
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Thanks for watching!